<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<title>David King</title>
	<link href="http://oodavid.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href="http://oodavid.com/"/>
	<updated>2016-04-08T16:33:18+01:00</updated>
	<id>http://oodavid.com/</id>
	<author>
		<name>David King</name>
		<email>david@oodavid.com</email>
	</author>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Improving the UX of AngularJS Filters</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2016/02/24/improving-the-ux-of-angular-filters.html"/>
		<updated>2016-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2016/02/24/improving-the-ux-of-angular-filters</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;ve used &lt;a href=&quot;https://angularjs.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;AngularJS&lt;/a&gt; you&#39;ll undoubtedly be familiar with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.angularjs.org/guide/filter&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;filter examples&lt;/a&gt;. When you type into the textboxthe array of items is magically filtered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This feature is fabulous. But because the filter looks at &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; properties in your array, it&#39;s not always obvious why certain items are in the list. Don&#39;t worry though, I&#39;ve got you covered!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://plnkr.co/edit/VapAS1D7snbMXdClJZqx?p=preview&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Play with this on Plunker.&lt;/a&gt; Or watch my Youtube video... Or both! Go crazy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;iframe width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/93JmNeMGgwM?cc_load_policy=1&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=93JmNeMGgwM&quot;&gt;View on Youtube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Khan Draw</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2015/12/18/khan-draw.html"/>
		<updated>2015-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2015/12/18/khan-draw</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been spending a lot of time using &lt;a href=&quot;http://khanacademy.org&quot;&gt;Khan-Academy&lt;/a&gt; to brush off some Math and Biology cobwebs. Great fun!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The format of the videos appeals to me; a simple sketch with voice-over. I decided to see if I could replicate their toolchain in the browser:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;A Sketching App&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;...which records the screen&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;...captures the microphone audio&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;...and spits out a video&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was initially concerned that screen recording would be impossible, but a quick search led me to a couple of great projects:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/muaz-khan/RecordRTC&quot;&gt;RecordRTC&lt;/a&gt; - for recording videos in the browser&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bgrins.github.io/videoconverter.js/&quot;&gt;videoconverter.js&lt;/a&gt; - a javascript port of ffmpeg, for merging and converting seperate video and audio streams&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Standing on the shoulders of these giants, I created &lt;a href=&quot;https://draw.oodavid.com/&quot;&gt;khan-draw&lt;/a&gt;! This is the output:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;iframe width=&quot;420&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ipukSqk1pTY&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;I made this in the browser!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The source-code is &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/oodavid/khan-draw&quot;&gt;available on github&lt;/a&gt;, but please give it a go at &lt;a href=&quot;https://draw.oodavid.com/&quot;&gt;draw.oodavid.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few limitations to the project, I&#39;ve made note of them on the project (click the &amp;quot;info&amp;quot; button)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Complexity</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2015/07/20/complexity.html"/>
		<updated>2015-07-20T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2015/07/20/complexity</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve just finished reading &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.co.uk/Complexity-Very-Short-Introduction-Introductions/dp/0199662541&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Complexity, A Very Short Introduction&lt;/a&gt;, what a cracking book! The idea that dynamic hierarchies can emerge from a simple set of physical or theoretical rules has been something that I&#39;ve always believed to be true, now I have a smattering of new vocabulary and ideas to draw upon when thinking about the subject, I feel blessed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/pGGljUS.jpg&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/MKdcnfm.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was pretty fortuitous in reading this book directly after &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.co.uk/Flash-Boys-Michael-Lewis/dp/0241003636&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Flash Boys&lt;/a&gt; as they harmonised wonderfully, the former giving me a gripping story to reference when reading the latter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Flash Boys&lt;/em&gt; is an interesting exposé about high-tech thieves lurking within the logical rules of the Stock Market - their existance isn&#39;t surprising (crooked banks? how cliché), the real story is how the perpetrators hid in plain sight by adding a few simple rules to the market, knowing exactly how to exploit them for massive profits. Their logic and approach is impressive, to be able to predict and adapt to the patterns that emerge from a few simple rule changes is something very few people can do, nobel laureate level intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s a pretty big subject, but I want to show you a quick example of this before looking at complexity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;How it &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; work&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trader A&lt;/strong&gt; buys 1,000 shares of &lt;strong&gt;Company A&lt;/strong&gt; on a single Stock Exchange&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The Exchange then attempts to buy the shares from other traders on the same exchange who are selling&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;If the Exchange can&#39;t fulfil the order internally then it will pass the order to &lt;strong&gt;other Exchanges&lt;/strong&gt; until the 1,000 shares have been sold&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;How adding a single rule screws things up&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above model shows how simple it should be, it looks innocent enough, but if you add an extra order-type that can be sent &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;Wait in the queue until someone tries to buy these shares, then buy shares first&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lets assume a 3rd party &amp;quot;&lt;strong&gt;Trader X&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;quot; has sent a buy command with this new order-type, remember he doesn&#39;t actually get the share until someone else tries to buy it, and because he sent the command first, he gets priorty, lets see how that routine looks now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trader A&lt;/strong&gt; buys 1,000 shares of &lt;strong&gt;Company A&lt;/strong&gt; on a single Stock Exchange&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The Exchange then attempts to buy the shares from other traders on the same exchange who are selling
		&lt;ul&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trader X&lt;/strong&gt; was ahead of the queue with the &amp;quot;wait and buy&amp;quot; command&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trader X&lt;/strong&gt; gets 1 share of &lt;strong&gt;Company A&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trader X&lt;/strong&gt; uses this as a &amp;quot;notification&amp;quot; to buy shares in &lt;strong&gt;Company A&lt;/strong&gt; on &lt;strong&gt;other Exchanges&lt;/strong&gt;, it does this &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; quickly&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;If the Exchange can&#39;t fulfil the order internally then it will pass the order to &lt;strong&gt;other Exchanges&lt;/strong&gt; until the 1,000 shares have been sold
		&lt;ul&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;It just so happens that &lt;strong&gt;Trader X&lt;/strong&gt; has shares on &lt;strong&gt;other Exchanges&lt;/strong&gt;, at a &lt;em&gt;slightly&lt;/em&gt; higher price than expected.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, adding a simple rule has made the routine look a lot more complicated, and &lt;strong&gt;Trader A&lt;/strong&gt; doesn&#39;t notice anything different as this happens in a fraction of a second. As far as he&#39;s concerned, he bought some shares from one exchange, and some from another, pretty normal. These techniques are called Front Running (using insider information to buy shares first) and Scalping (driving up the price ever so slightly and taking a little profit off the top).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s not all doom and gloom, &lt;a href=&quot;http://iextrading.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;IEX&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.liquidnet.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Liquidnet&lt;/a&gt;, are new markets attempting to simplify the system once more, as is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.irmagazine.com/articles/stock-exchanges-listings/20178/nyse-eliminate-several-complex-order-types-rein-hft/&quot;&gt;the NYSE&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;(I&#39;m not sure if I believe this one)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Complexity&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The science of Complexity is blurry, it&#39;s still being explored and discovered so there&#39;s no true consensus on how to define it. However it does have some agreed properties:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;It has a few simple parts / rules&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;That interact with each other in multiple ways&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;And hierarchies emerge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the case of a stock exchange we have rules (buy, sell, wait-and-buy), the interactions are many (front-running, scalping, baiting), we see hierarchies emerge (the market, exchanges, traders, high-frequency traders).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I couldn&#39;t recommend this book highly enough, it gets a bit mathematical in places, but it&#39;s worth it!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Practical Internationalisation</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2015/05/11/practical-internationalisation.html"/>
		<updated>2015-05-11T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2015/05/11/practical-internationalisation</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The biggest part of the latest release of Button Up! (v0.9.9) was translating the game to 11 new languages. The first stage was being able to load the game with a language pre-selected, then I decided I wanted to be able to toggle the language in-game, which meant that all &amp;quot;static&amp;quot; text must be dynamic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/iakDew9.png&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/x0efGLx.png&quot;&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;The game auto-detects the users language, but also allows new languages to be manually selected.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A few moving parts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it came to translating, the planning and programming was straightforward, as was getting machine translations, here&#39;s the basic requirements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;I need seperate JSON assets for each translation, ie:
		&lt;ul&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;en.json&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;fr.json&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;de.json&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;...&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;I must programatically download translation data to create the JSON assets
		&lt;ul&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;Google Sheets is ideal as it can expose data in simple formats&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;Google Sheets allows anyone to edit online&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;I should auto-detect the users language preference
		&lt;ul&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;GameClosure exposes the javascript property &lt;strong&gt;navigator.language&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;...which maps to &lt;a href=&quot;http://developer.android.com/reference/java/util/Locale.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Locale&lt;/a&gt; on Android&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;...and &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/library/ios/documentation/Cocoa/Reference/Foundation/Classes/NSLocale_Class/&quot;&gt;NSLocale&lt;/a&gt; on iOS&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;I need to create a &lt;strong&gt;lang&lt;/strong&gt; object with exposes some simple methods, ie:
		&lt;ul&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;lang.setLang(&#39;auto&#39;)&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;lang.setLang(&#39;de&#39;)&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;lang.getLanguageCode()&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;lang.getAvailableLanguages()&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;lang.get(&#39;notification_full_lives&#39;)&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Converting Google Sheets into JSON&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Google Sheet is setup with the languages as columns, and the keys as rows. In the title I&#39;ve also added the language name, code and native name for reference:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;iframe width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1VkwercRy30p6XVQj7bITTTuQMRJBWFuj509jc9tQeqg/pubhtml?widget=true&amp;amp;headers=false&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;The Button Up! translations, &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1VkwercRy30p6XVQj7bITTTuQMRJBWFuj509jc9tQeqg/pubhtml&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;view in new tab&lt;/a&gt; for easier reading&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pulling the data down into individual JSON assets is straightforward:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Firstly, publish the Google Sheet and get a link to it in CSV format:
		&lt;ul&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;File &amp;gt; Publish to the web...&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;On the dialog change &lt;strong&gt;Entire Document&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;Sheet1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;... and &lt;strong&gt;Web Page&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;Comma-separated values (.csv)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;Then copy the link&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Using your favourite programming language, read and parse the file into individual JSON assets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My PHP code is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;brush: php&quot;&gt;
&amp;lt;?php
$url    = &#39;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheet/pub?key=1VkwercRy30p6XVQj7bITTTuQMRJBWFuj509jc9tQeqg&amp;amp;single=true&amp;amp;gid=0&amp;amp;output=csv&#39;;
$data   = array(); // Our structured data
$langs  = array(); // Used to lookup the language related with a column number
$native = array(); // List of language names, in their native language
$key    = false;
$rowNum = 1;
if(($handle = fopen($url, &#39;r&#39;)) !== FALSE){
	while(($row = fgetcsv($handle, 10000, &#39;,&#39;)) !== FALSE){
		$cols = count($row);
		switch($rowNum){
			case 1:
				// First Row is the English name of the language, ie: French, German, Italian
				//   Do nothing
				break;
			case 2:
				// Second Row is the language tag, ie: en, es, fr
				for($c=1; $c&amp;lt;$cols; $c++){
					$langs[$c]      = $row[$c]; // 1=en, 2=es...
					$data[$row[$c]] = array();  // en={}, es={}
				}
				break;
			case 3:
				// Third Row is the language tag, ie: en, es, fr
				for($c=1; $c&amp;lt;$cols; $c++){
					$lang = $langs[$c];
					$native[$lang] = $row[$c];  // en=English, es=Español, fr=Français
				}
				break;
			default:
				// All remaining rows are the key:value store
				// The first column is the key - if it&#39;s BLANK then it&#39;s just representing more values for last key
				if($row[0]){
					$key = $row[0];
					foreach($data AS $k =&amp;gt; $v){
						$data[$k][$key] = array();
					}
				}
				// Loop the columns, append to the translation arrays
				for($c=1; $c&amp;lt;$cols; $c++){
					$lang = $langs[$c];
					$data[$lang][$key][] = $row[$c];
				}
				break;

		}
		$rowNum++;
	}
	fclose($handle);
	// Process the data, tidying up blanks etc.
	foreach($data AS $lang =&amp;gt; &amp;amp;$props){
		foreach($props AS $key =&amp;gt; &amp;amp;$value){
			$value = array_filter($value);      // Remove empty values from the array
			if(count($value) == 0){
				unset($data[$lang][$key]);      // Blank arrays are removed
			} else if(count($value) == 1){
				$data[$lang][$key] = $value[0]; // Arrays with one element are converted to strings
			}
		}
	}
	unset($props);
	// Clear out the old JSON files
	$files = glob(&#39;resources/lang/*&#39;);
	foreach($files as $file){
		if(is_file($file)){
			unlink($file);
		}
	}
	// Great, now create the JSON files
	foreach($data AS $lang =&amp;gt; $props){
		file_put_contents(&amp;quot;resources/lang/{$lang}.json&amp;quot;, json_encode($props, JSON_PRETTY_PRINT));
	}
	// And the languages
	file_put_contents(&#39;resources/lang/langs.json&#39;, json_encode($native, JSON_PRETTY_PRINT));
}
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To update the game with new translations, simply add the translations to the sheet, then run the script. Smashing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Getting the translations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially I wanted to use &lt;a href=&quot;https://unbabel.com/&quot;&gt;Unbabel&lt;/a&gt; to have human translations, but ended up just using a free Google Sheet addon called &lt;strong&gt;Translate My Sheet&lt;/strong&gt; (Add-Ons &amp;gt; Get add-ons &amp;gt; search for &amp;quot;translate&amp;quot;) - I&#39;ll probably move to Unbabel in due course, I just need to take a moment to read their documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve not had any native speakers take a look at the translations, and I&#39;m sure that Google has done some strange things, but what the hell, it&#39;s in the wild now! If anyone can cast a knowing eye over the game, I&#39;d be very grateful!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>The Inverse Kinematics of Lord Mountbutton</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2015/03/04/the-inverse-kinematics-of-lord-mountbutton.html"/>
		<updated>2015-03-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2015/03/04/the-inverse-kinematics-of-lord-mountbutton</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On the surface Button Up! is a simple casual game, but there&#39;s more than meets the eye when it comes to the FTUE (First Time User-Experience).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been through several iterations of &lt;em&gt;content&lt;/em&gt;, but the one element that felt &amp;quot;just right&amp;quot; is the dynamics of Lord Mountbutton. With a little back and forth with &lt;a href=&quot;gavinmcphail.com&quot;&gt;Gavin McPhail&lt;/a&gt; (graphics) I rigged him up in a few days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here I will describe the basic logic that goes into the Inverse Kinematics with a stretchy twist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/t4A10CV.gif&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/C9KS8HJ.gif&quot;&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Lord Mountbutton can point at anything on-screen&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In most Inverse Kinematics tutorials you will read about skeletons and bones etc. terms used to describe components of fixed length. Lord Mountbutton however, has a &amp;quot;telescopic&amp;quot; needle that allows us to extend the range of pointing. This required an extra step in the kinematic logic&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The forearm image contains the arm, hand &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; telescopic needle, &amp;quot;3-slicing&amp;quot; allows the image to stretch along the needle shaft:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/w8Q7Eou.png&quot;&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Forearm logic&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
	&lt;dt&gt;length a&lt;/dt&gt;
		&lt;dd&gt;the known variable length&lt;/dd&gt;
	&lt;dt&gt;length b&lt;/dt&gt;
		&lt;dd&gt;fixed length based on internal geometry&lt;/dd&gt;
	&lt;dt&gt;length c&lt;/dt&gt;
		&lt;dd&gt;sits exactly on the X-Axis, 3-slice scaling stretches this segment leaving the rest intact&lt;/dd&gt;
	&lt;dt&gt;angle A&lt;/dt&gt;
		&lt;dd&gt;fixed angle based on internal geometry&lt;/dd&gt;
	&lt;dt&gt;angle B&lt;/dt&gt;
		&lt;dd&gt;used to offset the overall asset angle to keep the arm visually straight&lt;/dd&gt;
	&lt;dt&gt;angle C&lt;/dt&gt;
		&lt;dd&gt;unused&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Essentially, we need to convert &lt;strong&gt;length a&lt;/strong&gt; into &lt;strong&gt;length c&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;angle B&lt;/strong&gt;, this can be acheived by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mathsisfun.com/algebra/trig-solving-ssa-triangles.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;solving the triangle&lt;/a&gt;. After that, it&#39;s a case of restricting the motion of the arm to natural looking angles and deciding which routine to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Attempt to calculate using inverse kinematics (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.khanacademy.org/computer-programming/inverse-kinematics-robot-arm/5648684600524800&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;example&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Bind the angles to a natural range&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;If the point has not been &amp;quot;touched&amp;quot;, stretch the forearm, accounting for internal geometry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simple as that!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/kE63hwi.png&quot;&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;The deconstructed Lord Mountbutton looks terrifying&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Button Up!</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2015/01/28/button-up.html"/>
		<updated>2015-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2015/01/28/button-up</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Molecule Match is now Button Up!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve had a lot of great feedback about Molecule Match, but a recurring gripe was that the learning curve was steep. Which has led to rather a few changes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;I&#39;ve ditched the chemical theme in favour of the haberdashery
		&lt;ul&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Atoms&lt;/strong&gt; are now &lt;strong&gt;Buttons&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bonds&lt;/strong&gt; are now &lt;strong&gt;Threads&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Molecules&lt;/strong&gt; are now &lt;strong&gt;Patterns&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cherries&lt;/strong&gt; are now &lt;strong&gt;Yarn&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The Tutorial has been improved (again)
		&lt;ul&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;I think the Tutorial will need constant updates as it&#39;s critical for onboarding players&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;I&#39;ve cobbled together a quick website
		&lt;ul&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://buttonupgame.com/&quot;&gt;buttonupgame.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;Finally gave Google AppEngine a whirl, love it.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;I&#39;ve enlisted some help! The game no longer looks or sounds like a coder made it
		&lt;ul&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://sijamaudio.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Simon James&lt;/a&gt; - audio&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://gavinmcphail.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Gavin Patrick McPhail&lt;/a&gt; - visual&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.oodavid.buttonup&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://buttonupgame.com/gfx/googleplay.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/button-up!/id957291486?mt=8&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://buttonupgame.com/gfx/appstore.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/7UL6RCM.png&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/Pj0pPvE.png&quot;&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Old theme and my graphics (left), vs New theme and Gavin&#39;s graphics (right)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;iframe width=&quot;250&quot; height=&quot;550&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZDWzx9OTfP0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;The audio adds an almost haptic dimension to the game!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do you think? Ready to play?&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Molecule Match, a Game</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2014/03/11/molecule-match-a-game.html"/>
		<updated>2014-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2014/03/11/molecule-match-a-game</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you&#39;re the type of person that hears &amp;quot;maths&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;science&amp;quot; and starts to have a seizure, chill out dude! This is a &lt;strong&gt;game&lt;/strong&gt; not an exam paper... &lt;small&gt;although I might cold-call you with spot questions when you least expect it.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For about 2 or 3 years I&#39;ve been toying with a game concept based on molecular structures, I&#39;ll give you the massively redacted brainstory:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;You know how I &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; like The Count of Monte Cristo? Yeah.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Remember that game Chiral? No? Well I do, it was awesome.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Amateur Psychology makes up a good chunk of my autodidactism.&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Especially addiction and manipulation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fuse those themes together&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And you get something that is so impossibly hard to describe, that people run for the hills! And by god I love an up-hill struggle. I&#39;m struggling up that hill to catch the people that run away, so that in my usual upbeat manner I can ramble on at them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or I could show a pretty picture...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/fQGxkFR.gif&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;480&quot;&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;I actually see little buttons not atoms, but hey, let me enjoy myself.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been told this might be an original puzzle dynamic. Which is pretty cool. I&#39;m not omniscient of course, but there&#39;s a big empty space in my grey matter where things like this should live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Wanna play?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve done a very naughty thing by introducing 3 concepts and then showing a daft gif of some brightly colored gubbins; if you trust me (which you should) you can install a pre-alpha on your phone and have a play. Really, this explains waaaay more than I can be bothered to write on my blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EDIT&lt;/strong&gt;: since writing this article, Molecule Match has evolved into Button Up! and is available to play:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/button-up!/id957291486?mt=8&quot;&gt;On iOS (iPhone / iPad)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.oodavid.buttonup&quot;&gt;On Android&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Just have to read more of my bullcroop?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read &lt;a href=&quot;http://forums.tigsource.com/index.php?topic=38408&quot;&gt;my development log on the TIGSource forums&lt;/a&gt;. There&#39;s lots there&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Easing Functions Refactored</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2013/11/11/easing-functions-refactored.html"/>
		<updated>2013-11-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2013/11/11/easing-functions-refactored</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In the 2002 book, &lt;strong&gt;&amp;quot;Robert Penner&#39;s Programming Macromedia Flash MX&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt; the author wrote a chapter about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.robertpenner.com/easing/penner_chapter7_tweening.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;tweening&lt;/a&gt;; a word you may now know as &amp;quot;easing&amp;quot;. Anyhoo, these easing functions have made their way into mainstream programming culture and have been ported over into every conceivable language and many popular frameworks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply, easing functions are a way to animate in &lt;a href=&quot;http://easings.net&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a smooth or interesting manner&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These functions have been all but unaltered for the past decade, however while looking into the relatively new &lt;a href=&quot;http://gameclosure.com/&quot;&gt;gameclosure&lt;/a&gt; framework I found an opportunity to contribute by adding these functions to their javascript codebase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I did the logical thing, read some background information, found a modern port (jQuery) and started dissecting the code... what I found was bewildering and confusing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Why do they accept 4 parameters?!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;t: current time&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;b: beginning value&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;c: change in value&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;d: duration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I might be missing the point, but these parameters make the functions difficult to read and complex to use outside of their intended animation scope. I &lt;em&gt;wrongly&lt;/em&gt; surmised that the functions would accept one parameter akin to &lt;strong&gt;Math.sin&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Math.cos&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;Math.tan&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; which the transformations and manipulations could be applied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I modified the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/danro/jquery-easing/blob/master/jquery.easing.js&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;jQuery easing functions&lt;/a&gt; to accept one parameter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;n - A value between 0 and 1&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you consider the above parameters we can assume a special scenario:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;t: current time&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Between 0 and 1&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;b: beginning value&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Always 0&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;c: change in value&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Always 1&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;d: duration&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Always 1&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Means that we can rewrite the functions to an extremely compact form, for example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;brush: javascript&quot;&gt;
	// Original Function
	easeInQuad = function (t, b, c, d) {
		return c * (t /= d) * t + b;
	};
	// Swapping our special values
	easeInQuad = function (n) {
		return 1 * (n /= 1) * n + 0;
	};
	// Refactored
	easeInQuad = function (n) {
		return n * n;
	};
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can quickly see that my version is &lt;em&gt;MUCH&lt;/em&gt; more readable. Furthermore, I&#39;ve found an amazing oddity in the jQuery port of the elastic easing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;brush: javascript&quot;&gt;
	// Original
	easeInElastic = function (t, b, c, d) {
		var s=1.70158;var p=0;var a=c;
		if (t==0) return b;  if ((t/=d)==1) return b+c;  if (!p) p=d*.3;
		if (a &amp;lt; Math.abs(c)) { a=c; var s=p/4; }
		else var s = p/(2*Math.PI) * Math.asin (c/a);
		return -(a*Math.pow(2,10*(t-=1)) * Math.sin( (t*d-s)*(2*Math.PI)/p )) + b;
	};
	// Expanded
	easeInElastic = function (t, b, c, d) {
		var s = 1.70158;
		var p = 0;
		var a = c;
		if (t == 0) {
			return b;
		}
		if ((t /= d) == 1) {
			return b + c;
		}
		if (!p) {
			p = d * .3;
		}
		if (a &amp;lt; Math.abs(c)) {
			a = c;
			var s = p / 4;
		} else {
			var s = p / (2 * Math.PI) * Math.asin(c / a);
		}
		return -(a * Math.pow(2, 10 * (t -= 1)) * Math.sin((t * d - s) * (2 * Math.PI) / p)) + b;
	};
	// Swapping our special values and adding comments...
	easeInElastic = function (n) {
		var s = 1.70158;
		var p = 0;
		var a = 1;
		if (n == 0) {
			return 0;
		}
		if ((n /= 1) == 1) {
			return 0 + 1;
		}
		// &quot;p&quot; is ALWAYS 0, why set it above?
		if (!p) {
			p = 1 * .3;
		}
		// &quot;s&quot; is ALWAYS replaced regardless, why set it above?
		if (a &amp;lt; Math.abs(1)) {
			// &quot;a&quot; is already set to 1... err...
			// not that it matters, as 1 is NEVER &amp;lt; 1 thus this is NEVER executed
			a = 1;
			var s = p / 4;
		} else {
			var s = p / (2 * Math.PI) * Math.asin(1 / a);
		}
		return -(a * Math.pow(2 , 10 * (n -= 1)) * Math.sin((n * 1 - s) * (2 * Math.PI) / p )) + 0;
	};
	// Refactoring A
	easeInElastic = function (n) {
		if (n == 0) {
			return 0;
		}
		if (n == 1) {
			return 1;
		}
		var p = 0.3;
		var s = p / (2 * Math.PI) * Math.asin(1); // This is ALWAYS 0.075
		return -(a * Math.pow(2 , 10 * (n -= 1)) * Math.sin((n * 1 - s) * (2 * Math.PI) / p )) + 0;
	};
	// Refactoring B
	easeInElastic = function (n) {
		if (n == 0) return 0;
		if (n == 1) return 1;
		var p = 0.3;
		var s = 0.075;	// p / (2 * Math.PI) * Math.asin(1)
		return -(Math.pow(2, 10 * (n -= 1)) * Math.sin((n - s) * (2 * Math.PI) / p));
	};
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may have missed it, but there&#39;s a LOT of redundant code and needless logical checks; the resulting function is not only faster, but in my mind &lt;strong&gt;just better&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Source Code&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My full refactor is available on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/oodavid/timestep/blob/master/src/animate/transitions.js&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;github here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>NexGen is Hiring!</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2013/10/14/nexgen-is-hiring.html"/>
		<updated>2013-10-14T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2013/10/14/nexgen-is-hiring</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Our company is looking to hire a &amp;quot;Magician&#39;s Assistant&amp;quot; to help me in my day-to-day; do you want to be my Debby McGee?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;We need to hire an assistant who can help me with my ever growing workload.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;I&#39;m the Software Architect at Lucion Environmental Limited.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The company has around 130 staff, but only one software chap (me).&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The work will be varied within a &amp;quot;helpdesk&amp;quot; role, expect things like:
		&lt;ul&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;Managing internal (staff) and external (our clients) requests.&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;Working directly with a mature database to analyse data.&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;Writing Documentation and user-guides.&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;Making minor changes to our software.&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;Being the first line of defense between me and the world of distractions.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For full details &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lucion.co.uk/nexgen-software-facilitator/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;go to the Lucion site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>A Workout for Productivity</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2013/09/30/a-workout-for-productivity.html"/>
		<updated>2013-09-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2013/09/30/a-workout-for-productivity</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;style&gt;
	#setup			{margin: 0 0 20px 0; text-align: center;}
	#setup input	{width: 40px; border: none; padding: 3px; text-align: center;}
	#setup span		{display: none; padding: 0 0 0 5px; color: #F6B82F; font-weight: bold;}
	.exercise		{width: 320px; margin: 10px 14px; padding: 5px; border: 1px solid #DDDDDD; float: left; text-align: center; font-size: 18px;}
	.exercise img	{display: block; margin: 0 auto 6px;}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My friends and more regular readers will know that I used to be part of a startup called &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://happie.st&quot;&gt;happie.st&lt;/a&gt;; we made a system that tracked and rewarded activites that make you happy; such as eating well, meditating, being grateful and &lt;strong&gt;exercising&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a funny sort of way, I really miss that company; it might just be that I (still) think the idea is splendid and just badly executed, but the concept struck a cord with me that I&#39;m unwilling to unstrike. Perpetual self-improvement is thoroughly embedded in &lt;em&gt;American&lt;/em&gt; mainstream thinking it seems weird that there&#39;s barely a market here in the UK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago I decided to find an equipment-less exercise routine that I could do at home and came across the &lt;a href=&quot;biggestloser.com/fitness/exercises/daily-home-workout&quot;&gt;Biggest Loser Daily Home Workout&lt;/a&gt; and have been exercising with this routine every day. And holy moly has it made a difference to my productivity at work!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I have a compulsion to research, review and improve on everything; I&#39;ve ended up tweaking the routine to add some light dumbell exercises, stretches and powerball usage. And I&#39;ve also knocked up a little widget that scales up the workout with consequitive sessions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;form id=&quot;setup&quot; onsubmit=&quot;return false;&quot;&gt;
	Workout number: &lt;input type=&quot;number&quot; value=&quot;1&quot; min=&quot;1&quot; step=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
	&lt;button&gt;Start Workout&lt;/button&gt;
	&lt;span&gt;maximum!&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On day 1 you get the minimum routine (about 10 minutes) and by day 30 all exercises scale up to the maximum I have time to do (about 25 minutes).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;clearfix&quot;&gt;

	&lt;!--a class=&quot;exercise&quot; href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;
		Dynamic Stretching A
	&lt;/a--&gt;

	&lt;!--a class=&quot;exercise&quot; href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;
		Dynamic Stretching B
	&lt;/a--&gt;

	&lt;a class=&quot;exercise&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.biggestloser.com/resources/exercises/50-jumping-jacks&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.biggestloser.com/sites/default/files/BLDolvett2.1.13_033_0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;180&quot;&gt;
		&lt;span data-min=&quot;50&quot; data-max=&quot;100&quot;&gt;??&lt;/span&gt; Jumping Jacks
	&lt;/a&gt;

	&lt;a class=&quot;exercise&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.biggestloser.com/resources/exercises/15-crunches&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.biggestloser.com/sites/default/files/BLDolvett2.1.13_037.jpg&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;180&quot;&gt;
		&lt;span data-min=&quot;15&quot; data-max=&quot;30&quot;&gt;??&lt;/span&gt; Crunches
	&lt;/a&gt;

	&lt;a class=&quot;exercise&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.biggestloser.com/resources/exercises/10-tricep-dips&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.biggestloser.com/sites/default/files/BLDolvett2.1.13_034.jpg&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;180&quot;&gt;
		&lt;span data-min=&quot;10&quot; data-max=&quot;25&quot;&gt;??&lt;/span&gt; Tricep Dips
	&lt;/a&gt;

	&lt;a class=&quot;exercise&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.biggestloser.com/resources/exercises/5-push-ups&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.biggestloser.com/sites/default/files/BLDolvett2.1.13_041.jpg&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;180&quot;&gt;
		&lt;span data-min=&quot;5&quot; data-max=&quot;20&quot;&gt;??&lt;/span&gt; Push Ups
	&lt;/a&gt;

	&lt;a class=&quot;exercise&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.biggestloser.com/resources/exercises/10-squats&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.biggestloser.com/sites/default/files/BLDolvett2.1.13_048.jpg&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;180&quot;&gt;
		&lt;span data-min=&quot;10&quot; data-max=&quot;30&quot;&gt;??&lt;/span&gt; Squats
	&lt;/a&gt;

	&lt;a class=&quot;exercise&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.biggestloser.com/resources/exercises/10-lunges-each-leg&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.biggestloser.com/sites/default/files/BLDolvett2.1.13_052.jpg&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;180&quot;&gt;
		&lt;span data-min=&quot;10&quot; data-max=&quot;25&quot;&gt;??&lt;/span&gt; Lunges (Each Leg)
	&lt;/a&gt;

	&lt;a class=&quot;exercise&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.biggestloser.com/resources/exercises/10-standing-calf-raises&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.biggestloser.com/sites/default/files/BLDolvett2.1.13_055.jpg&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;180&quot;&gt;
		&lt;span data-min=&quot;10&quot; data-max=&quot;30&quot;&gt;??&lt;/span&gt; Standing Calf Raises
	&lt;/a&gt;

	&lt;a class=&quot;exercise&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.biggestloser.com/resources/exercises/15-toe-touches-each-leg&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.biggestloser.com/sites/default/files/BLDolvett2.1.13_067.jpg&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;180&quot;&gt;
		&lt;span data-min=&quot;10&quot; data-max=&quot;25&quot;&gt;??&lt;/span&gt; Toe Touches
	&lt;/a&gt;

	&lt;a class=&quot;exercise&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.biggestloser.com/resources/exercises/15-rotating-elbow-planks&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.biggestloser.com/sites/default/files/BLDolvett2.1.13_063.jpg&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;180&quot;&gt;
		&lt;span data-min=&quot;15&quot; data-max=&quot;30&quot;&gt;??&lt;/span&gt; Rotating Elbow Planks
	&lt;/a&gt;

	&lt;a class=&quot;exercise&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.biggestloser.com/resources/exercises/30-sec-plank&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.biggestloser.com/sites/default/files/BLDolvett2.1.13_046.jpg&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;180&quot;&gt;
		&lt;span data-min=&quot;30&quot; data-max=&quot;60&quot;&gt;??&lt;/span&gt;-sec Plank
	&lt;/a&gt;

	&lt;a class=&quot;exercise&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.dumbbell-exercises.com/top-10/index.html#2&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.dumbbell-exercises.com/exercises/biceps/images/2.gif&quot;&gt;
		&lt;span data-min=&quot;10&quot; data-max=&quot;25&quot;&gt;??&lt;/span&gt; Alternated Biceps Curls
	&lt;/a&gt;

	&lt;a class=&quot;exercise&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.dumbbell-exercises.com/top-10/index.html#3&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.dumbbell-exercises.com/exercises/shoulders/images/5.gif&quot;&gt;
		&lt;span data-min=&quot;10&quot; data-max=&quot;25&quot;&gt;??&lt;/span&gt; Shoulder Press
	&lt;/a&gt;

	&lt;a class=&quot;exercise&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;
		&lt;span data-min=&quot;20&quot; data-max=&quot;45&quot;&gt;??&lt;/span&gt;-sec Powerball Forearm (each)
	&lt;/a&gt;

	&lt;a class=&quot;exercise&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;
		&lt;span data-min=&quot;20&quot; data-max=&quot;45&quot;&gt;??&lt;/span&gt;-sec Powerball Bicep (each)
	&lt;/a&gt;

	&lt;a class=&quot;exercise&quot; href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;
		4-min Shower
	&lt;/a&gt;

	&lt;a class=&quot;exercise&quot; href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;
		Breakfast
	&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>MySQL Procedures and Parameters</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2013/09/26/mysql-procedures-and-parameters.html"/>
		<updated>2013-09-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2013/09/26/mysql-procedures-and-parameters</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When it comes to databases, I&#39;ve tried to keep myself in the know about all the tools, features and best-practices even if I never utilise them. It&#39;s useful to be aware of the things you have yet to learn so that should you ever come accross a new problem your ability to think outside of the box is improved by an incling of an idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyhow, this week I&#39;ve finally needed to use MySQL PROCEDURES and TRIGGERS to help compliment some of the more complex queries we need to run &lt;em&gt;(the details of which are beyond the scope of this wee blog post)&lt;/em&gt;. And I quickly came about an issue regarding PARAMETERS that has had me scratching my head for some time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/trigger.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;the internal mechanism of TRIGGERs were still a mystery&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure--&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The evolution of a PROCEDURE&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lets start with a simple SQL query, you want to increment a column for a specific row:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre id=&quot;sql1&quot; class=&quot;brush: sql&quot;&gt;
	UPDATE `mytable`
		SET `mycolumn` = `mycolumn` + 1
		WHERE `id` = 1234;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then you want to make your query more dynamic by utilising User-Defined Variables:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;...maybe you are using prepared statements to similar effect...&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre id=&quot;sql2&quot; class=&quot;brush: sql&quot;&gt;
	SET @myid = 1234;
	UPDATE `mytable`
		SET `mycolumn` = `mycolumn` + 1
		WHERE `id` = @myid;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally you decide create a PROCEDURE that you can call like a function:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre id=&quot;sql3&quot; class=&quot;brush: sql&quot;&gt;
	DELIMITER $$
		DROP PROCEDURE IF EXISTS `MyProcedure` $$
		CREATE PROCEDURE MyProcedure(IN myid INT)
		BEGIN
			UPDATE `mytable`
				SET `mycolumn` = `mycolumn` + 1
				WHERE `id` = myid;
		END $$
	DELIMITER ;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That procedure is then stored within the database and can be used by any connection later:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;brush: sql&quot;&gt;
	CALL MyProcedure(1234);
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Works a treat. But to get to that functional PROCEDURE I took a massive, confusing detour...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Where I went wrong&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you look at the 3 statements above you will notice:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The first uses an explicit &lt;a href=&quot;#sql1&quot;&gt;1234&lt;/a&gt; within the statement&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The second uses the &lt;a href=&quot;#sql2&quot;&gt;@myid&lt;/a&gt; User-Defined Variable&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The third uses a &lt;a href=&quot;#sql3&quot;&gt;myid&lt;/a&gt; Parameter variable
		&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note the lack of @-sign&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following PROCEDURE uses BOTH @variables and paramenters:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;brush: sql&quot;&gt;
	DELIMITER $$
		DROP PROCEDURE IF EXISTS `MyProcedure` $$
		CREATE PROCEDURE MyProcedure(IN myvar VARCHAR(255))
		BEGIN
			SELECT myvar, @myvar ;
		END $$
	DELIMITER ;
	-- SET @myvar then call the procedure
	SET @myvar = &#39;variable&#39;;
	CALL MyProcedure(&#39;parameter&#39;);

	-- +----------+-----------+
	-- | myvar    | @myvar    |
	-- +----------+-----------+
	-- | variable | parameter |
	-- +----------+-----------+
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see that the PROCEDURE has access to both the User-Defined variables AND the parameters. Very confusing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lessons learned? MySQL PROCEDURES have access to Session scope. I don&#39;t know why, but I wouldn&#39;t have expected that.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>TDD - I need help!</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2013/08/30/tdd-i-need-help.html"/>
		<updated>2013-08-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2013/08/30/tdd-i-need-help</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Test-Driven-Development. I understand the principles, I&#39;ve read the books, I&#39;ve gazed at source codes and other projects that successfully employ it, and yet I still don&#39;t use it in my work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been developing &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lucion.co.uk/nexgen/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;NexGen&lt;/a&gt; since July 2011 and it&#39;s been operational and profitable since May 2012; I&#39;ve released almost daily updates to the program and is now in a sort of plateaux where everything functions as expected and most of the remaining roadmap items are &amp;quot;nice to have&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main problem I have is that my software is large, mature and mostly bug-free; retrofitting TDD could &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;add&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; bugs!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Err, so why do you want to use TDD?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;If a company’s own research does not make a product obsolete, another’s will&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;cite&gt;Theodore Levitt&lt;/cite&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m not content with it&#39;s current incarnation, I want it simpler, faster and more useful. Further than that I want to be confident that if / when I leave the company and hand my work over to another developer that he has all the necessary tools to maintain and develop the product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A big part of that is TDD; how could a stranger be confident that he hasn&#39;t b0rken everything? I think TDD would give that confidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/dilbert-new-guy.gif&quot;&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;poor sod&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Can you help?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t want to rewrite my code, but I do want to be able to test it. All of my important features are centred around database operations; as such my tests could be summed up as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;When I perform &amp;quot;X&amp;quot;, the database MUST have valid structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything I&#39;ve read about TDD has skirted around databases (mostly ignoring it altogether) and as such I have no inroad or lead to follow in order to design the tests that I deem most important.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>And so we are married...</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2013/08/28/and-so-we-are-married.html"/>
		<updated>2013-08-28T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2013/08/28/and-so-we-are-married</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;27&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; of July 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/married.jpg&quot;&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;She&#39;s a lucky girl and she knows it&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wedding, Honeymoon, New House. Made with 100% traditional ingredients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ll be back blogging soon, I&#39;ve got Android, Mobile Database-Syncronisation logic and various other gubbins, but as you might expect I&#39;ve had to take some time to get hitched, bugger off to warmer climes then play catchup at work!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Sitting on the anti-porn fence</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2013/07/23/sitting-on-the-anti-porn-fence.html"/>
		<updated>2013-07-23T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2013/07/23/sitting-on-the-anti-porn-fence</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;You&#39;ve probably read that the government wants to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-23401076&quot;&gt;Block Access to Pornography by Default&lt;/a&gt;, you may have read articles for and against. Me? I want to be in the smack bang in the middle argueing both sides for two reasons: it&#39;s fun and it&#39;s &lt;strong&gt;right&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;We need to protect our children &lt;small&gt;I agree!&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://philbradley.typepad.com/phil_bradleys_weblog/2013/07/why-blocking-pornography-is-an-offense-against-all-of-us.html&quot;&gt;Phil Bradley&lt;/a&gt; would have you think that if you want to protect your kids you can do so by installing a netnanny on your home PC:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;You can add filtering software yourself if you want to protect your children. The woman from the (I think) NSPCC was complaining that it was &#39;too difficult&#39; for parents to do it. If parents are capable of buying a computer and setting it up, they&#39;re capable of installing software that is designed to be easy to do just that. How insulting - how insulting to assume that it&#39;s too complicated for people to do. And, if it is, then parents need to damn well step up to the plate and learn how to use the computer in their household. They either care enough about their children&#39;s safety to do something about it, or they don&#39;t.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Err, yes, yes it is complicated; I couldn&#39;t confidently do it and I&#39;m technically minded! His argument appears set in the &#39;90s when there was a single shared family PC; but here in the future we have mobile phones, games consoles and TVs that can access anything online. Oh yeah, and they can do it over mobile networks too. So that&#39;s not an option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;We need to protect our freedoms &lt;small&gt;Err, I also agree!&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an open-source contributer I have directly gained by the reality of this; our &amp;quot;freedoms&amp;quot; have enabled me to learn a skilled trade (programming) and help others do the same. I can communicate accross the globe to my peers in countries with vastly differring political and social environments, I learn from these people and hopefully they learn from me too. Freedom means I can have my opinion, but it also means that I should be able to change my mind when I hear your opinion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Sit on the fence!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s a story that I rarely divulge. When I was very young, my Grandad told me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;black people are just white criminals painted black, you can tell this is true because they pray when they&#39;re sprayed and that&#39;s why their palms are white.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...and at 4 years old I knew it was true: Grandad told me so. I learned otherwise when I repeated it to my teacher at school - what a bollocking I received! And in the moment I didn&#39;t know why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That bollocking and subsequent remorse was the most important lesson I received at school. The truth is, all parties were good people: my teacher certainly, I hope I am and my Grandad was a good person &lt;em&gt;(his sense of humor belonged in the army in Africa is all)&lt;/em&gt; and somehow I managed to harbour a truly awful belief. From that day on I&#39;ve tried not to take sides because I can never know the all facts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mind you, it made me &lt;strong&gt;love&lt;/strong&gt; playing devils advocate! Out of the frying pan and all that...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;So what should we do?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think we should say: &lt;strong&gt;IF&lt;/strong&gt; the law was passed, how can we protect our civil liberties?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can we come up with a solution that satisfies &lt;em&gt;both&lt;/em&gt; parties? To do this everyone would need to put their toys back in the pram; stop screaming and start thinking. I mean having a right good old think. This is just a puzzle to be solved right?&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>A Simple Way to Smash Your Todo List</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2013/07/10/a-simple-way-to-smash-your-todo-list.html"/>
		<updated>2013-07-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2013/07/10/a-simple-way-to-smash-your-todo-list</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am a big fan of todo lists, I like to ponder my workload on the ride to the office and jot a list every morning as I sit down at the desk; it helps keep me productive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s best to allocate times to your tasks to help visualise how your day will go. In doing this you will know what needs to be done before lunch, and before you go home etc. Invariably there will be too much on the list, but that&#39;s OK as it will keep your day jam packed and productive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have work that requires your focus on a computer screen, may I suggest you...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;...unplug your laptop and go somewhere quiet!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one comes from my habit of taking my laptop home from work without a charger; that way I know that I wont waste my evening being a zombie when I should be doing other things. Like living my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/battery.png&quot; width=&quot;384&quot; height=&quot;123&quot;&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;As your battery depletes you &lt;strong&gt;must&lt;/strong&gt; become more productive&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m writing this article &amp;quot;unplugged&amp;quot; as part of a set of tasks that &lt;strong&gt;will&lt;/strong&gt; take me 3 hours. I&#39;m confident in my timing as I only ever get 3 hours out of this poxy battery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right then, gotta dash, stuff to do and all that!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Accessible Online Banking Confirmation</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2013/07/01/accessible-online-banking-confirmation.html"/>
		<updated>2013-07-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2013/07/01/accessible-online-banking-confirmation</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When you setup a new recipient online, your bank will ask to jump through a telephonic security hoop to confirm that you aren&#39;t a naughty hacker. Quite rightly so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However this becomes an issue if you have hearing issues, back in August 2011 I had a conversation with &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/AskLloydsTSB/status/109233455879036928&quot;&gt;@AskLloydsTSB&lt;/a&gt; about adding some on-screen instructions detailing the timings of the call as a simple workaround.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They did it within a few hours&lt;/strong&gt;. I consider this the best piece of reactive design I have ever experienced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;It&#39;s no longer suitable&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though my hearing is fine, I &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; use the non-hearing approach to make sure that it&#39;s still functional. Today it failed me. The automated message has changed and I have realised that the transfer amount also affects the timings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;TEN PENCE&amp;quot; - a mere moment&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;ONE THOUSAND, NINE HUNDRED AND TWENTY THREE POUNDS AND SEVENTY TWO PENCE&amp;quot; - somewhat longer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The proposal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By sending the 4-digit code to the user via SMS they could enter it on-screen for the same level of security (verifying the user is who they say they are). Furthermore it will be FULLY accessible to the hard-of-hearing community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interface-wise we only need one additional page to deal with the SMS instructions and input; there&#39;s no need to have an additional screen to choose between SMS and Voice as this choice can be added to the &amp;quot;create new recipient page&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/lloyds-auth-A.png&quot;&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Current User-Experience would be unchanged as Voice is selected by default&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/lloyds-auth-B.png&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Those requiring SMS confirmation get the alternative Confirmation screen&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;script type=&quot;gviz&quot; data-layout=&quot;dot&quot;&gt;&lt;![CDATA[
digraph G {
  graph [
    truecolor=true
    bgcolor=&quot;#FFFFFF00&quot;
  ];
  node [
    style=filled
    fillcolor=&quot;#FFFFFF&quot;
    color=&quot;#0F192A&quot;
    fontcolor=&quot;#0F192A&quot;
    penwidth=2
    shape=box
  ];
  new         [label=&quot;Setup New Recipient\nHow would you like to confirm?&quot;];
  chooseSMS   [label=&quot;Confirm with SMS&quot;  shape=&quot;none&quot; fillcolor=&quot;transparent&quot; fontcolor=&quot;#F6B82F&quot;];
  chooseVoice [label=&quot;Confirm with Call&quot; shape=&quot;none&quot; fillcolor=&quot;transparent&quot; fontcolor=&quot;#F62F41&quot;];
  receive     [label=&quot;Receive Code via SMS&quot;];
  enter       [label=&quot;Enter Code On-Screen&quot;];
  view        [label=&quot;Show Code On-Screen&quot;];
  call        [label=&quot;Receive Phone Call&quot;];
  enter2      [label=&quot;Enter Code On-Call&quot;];
  thanks      [label=&quot;Thanks for confirming your identity&quot;];
  new -&gt; chooseSMS -&gt; receive -&gt; enter -&gt; thanks [color=&quot;#F6B82F&quot; penwidth=2];
  new -&gt; chooseVoice -&gt; view -&gt; call -&gt; enter2 -&gt; thanks [color=&quot;#F62F41&quot; penwidth=2];
}
]]&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;As you can see, the changes would have minimal effect on the interface, and with my experience&lt;br&gt;as a programmer I&#39;d be confident that the backend logic would be straightforward too.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Addendum&lt;/strong&gt;: To the LloydsTSB employees reading this; I hope that you take these graphics and arguments, take them to your boss and impress the shit out of them. I don&#39;t even care if you pass it off as your brainchild and get a fat rise and employee of the month, if it gets done you will make the hard-of-hearing community proud!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And with that I must bid LloydsTSB Godspeed!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Converting Google Spreadsheeets to JSON</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2013/06/24/converting-google-spreadsheeets-to-json.html"/>
		<updated>2013-06-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2013/06/24/converting-google-spreadsheeets-to-json</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Todays Blog post has been brought to you in the format of an exremely busy person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brevity is the new levity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Create a &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheet/ccc?key=0AmqTMmxb4MxEdE9vUHVPdWs1WjlJR1JlbFJubi14VkE&amp;amp;usp=sharing&quot;&gt;simple Google Spreadsheet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Publish it (it can still be privately editable)&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Download my &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/oodavid/5800765&quot;&gt;script (github gist)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Tweak the settings in the code
		&lt;ul&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;Link to the published CSV file&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;Set the column names&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;Run the page&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Et viola! You have a formatted JSON object for use in your projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Making use of the tool&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The usefulness might not be immediately apparent...&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When working on NexGen I am required to complete projects and add features in a rapid manner. We have all-but-removed the need for meetings instead agreeing that prototype development by gut-instinct eclipses the time spent deliberating and group planning. Standard Agile stuff really.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Setup&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Our Mobile App has many (Risk) definitions in JSON format.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;These Risks are created and managed by one of our Directors on Google Drive.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Changes are infrequent, but important.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Solution&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The Director continues to work in his usual manner&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;I use &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/drive/answer/91588?hl=en&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;onchange&amp;quot; notifications&lt;/a&gt; to make sure I know when he updates the spreadsheet.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;This script is then manually used by me, and the mobile app updated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;https://gist.github.com/oodavid/5800765.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Are you beasting it?</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2013/06/03/are-you-beasting-it.html"/>
		<updated>2013-06-03T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2013/06/03/are-you-beasting-it</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It occurred to me recently that I can group my working mood into 2 broad categories:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beasting it&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pros&lt;/strong&gt; - very accepting of risk, highly productive, good for delivering&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cons&lt;/strong&gt; - eventual burn out&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meditation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pros&lt;/strong&gt; - risk aware, blue-sky thinking, good for planning&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cons&lt;/strong&gt; - situational anxiety&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every day has a balance of the two, depending on the demands on your time. They&#39;re like the Yin and Yang of productivity, opposing forces rendered meaningless in the absence of the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Diagnosis - too much beasting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you beast it too much you &lt;strong&gt;will&lt;/strong&gt; burn out. Burning out means being tired, losing focus and making mistakes. When you burn out you must resist the temptation to panic at your mistakes and beast it some more - you should take the time to relax and mediate. Your issues will dissolve with perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This happenned to me this weekend; I was at the end of a long programming session and was in need of a break, a panicked email arrives saying that &amp;quot;the wheels have come off!&amp;quot;. Very worrying and in need of immediate attention. Instinctively I jumped head-first into the problem and found myself quickly gettting stressed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer lay in a nice long walk in the park, it was sunny and beautiful. By the time I got home I knew everything I needed to do, in the order to do it and it was easy, if a little time-consuming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Diagnosis - too much mediation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spending too long pondering your isses will quickly become immobilising. There will always be pitfalls, what-ifs and unexpected problems, it&#39;s impossible to plan for all eventualities! If you have an impossible problem that you cannot figure out often the best answer is to unleash the beast and just crack on!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me this tends to happen before embarking on a big change, whether it&#39;s cultural, logistical or technical sometimes you just need to have a go even if it means returning to the drawing board in a few minutes, doing is revealing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The right balance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My spirit animal is probably a Manatee. Except this manatee has a Leopard Seal as &lt;em&gt;it&#39;s&lt;/em&gt; spirit animal. Kinda like a matroska. Make of this what you will.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://fc04.deviantart.net/fs70/i/2011/102/7/f/baby_manatee_by_peteyong-d3dt5ki.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;I hope you didn&#39;t expect my periodical blog not to have some nonesense?!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Addendum&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure, you could say that this is Scrum planning and sprinting, however for my work on NexGen I have become a kind of programming schizophrenic which includes both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;On one hand, we must NEVER lose sight of our long-term objectives, we have worked hard to plot a route to scaleabilty and success - for this, Scrum and Agile are perfect.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;On the other, we must ALWAYS react in a timely manner to the demands of our clients and stakeholders, critical to our reputation and cashflow - for these, &amp;quot;continuous integration&amp;quot; is required.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>The Cost of Complexity in Software</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2013/05/01/the-cost-of-complexity-in-software.html"/>
		<updated>2013-05-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2013/05/01/the-cost-of-complexity-in-software</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When a product grows in complexity it can be difficult to justify to clients, stakeholders and even other developers why adding a single feature can be such an involved process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many methodologies to use when developing complex software &lt;em&gt;(Agile, TDD, DRY, XP etc)&lt;/em&gt; however I would like to share an analogy to explain the rationale behind such practices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Spagetti Analogy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lets imagine a simple, completed application; it has 5 views (A-E) and all is functional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;script type=&quot;gviz&quot; data-layout=&quot;dot&quot;&gt;&lt;![CDATA[
	digraph G {
		graph [
			truecolor=true
			bgcolor=&quot;#FFFFFF00&quot;
		];
		node [
			style=filled
			fillcolor=&quot;#FFFFFF&quot;
		];
		// Graph
		A; B; C; D; E;
	}
	]]&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Your client may think of the app like this, ie: only what they can see&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In reality there is more than meets the eye; those 5 views might pass data around, update a database and do other wonderful things in the background, a more accurate expression of the app might be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;script type=&quot;gviz&quot; data-layout=&quot;circo&quot;&gt;&lt;![CDATA[
	digraph G {
		graph [
			truecolor=true
			bgcolor=&quot;#FFFFFF00&quot;
		];
		node [
			style=filled
			fillcolor=&quot;#FFFFFF&quot;
		];
		// Graph
		A -&gt; B -&gt; C -&gt; D -&gt; E -&gt; A;
		D -&gt; B -&gt; A;
		C -&gt; E;
		C -&gt; A;
		C -&gt; C;
	}
	]]&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;As a developer you will know how they link together&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even now you&#39;re talking a different language to your client!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Just add a new view&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we want to add a new view (X) to the app, your client can be forgiven if they think we only need to do this - after all their view of the product can be substantially different to yours&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;script type=&quot;gviz&quot; data-layout=&quot;dot&quot;&gt;&lt;![CDATA[
	digraph G {
		graph [
			truecolor=true
			bgcolor=&quot;#FFFFFF00&quot;
		];
		node [
			style=filled
			fillcolor=&quot;#FFFFFF&quot;
		];
		X [
			fillcolor=&quot;#000000&quot;
			color=transparent
			fontcolor=&quot;#FFFFFF&quot;
		];
		// Graph
		A; B; C; D; E; X;
	}
	]]&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If only it were that simple! Lets consider how this new view might sit inside the app as we know it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;script type=&quot;gviz&quot; data-layout=&quot;circo&quot;&gt;&lt;![CDATA[
	digraph G {
		graph [
			truecolor=true
			bgcolor=&quot;#FFFFFF00&quot;
		];
		node [
			style=filled
			fillcolor=&quot;#FFFFFF&quot;
		];
		X [
			fillcolor=&quot;#000000&quot;
			color=transparent
			fontcolor=&quot;#FFFFFF&quot;
		];
		A -&gt; B -&gt; C -&gt; D -&gt; E -&gt; A;
		D -&gt; B -&gt; A;
		C -&gt; E;
		C -&gt; A;
		C -&gt; C;
		X -&gt; A [style=dotted color=&quot;#FFFFFF&quot;];
		X -&gt; B [style=dotted color=&quot;#FFFFFF&quot;];
		X -&gt; C [style=dotted color=&quot;#FFFFFF&quot;];
		X -&gt; D [style=dotted color=&quot;#FFFFFF&quot;];
		X -&gt; E [style=dotted color=&quot;#FFFFFF&quot;];
	}
	]]&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previously we had 10 connections to manage, now we have 15! That&#39;s significantly more work than we originally expected!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;How is this possible?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, as software grows in size I believe it grows exponentially in complexity - or rather, it &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; grow exponentially. There are many things that you can do to minimise the issue of complexity that I would consider good programming practices but ultimately as you work on your application it will become more and more time-consuming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&#39;t despair, just be an awesome programmer and manage expectations!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;It&#39;s just this little thing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next time you hear a peer or client ask for just a little tweak and you have trouble explaining the issue at large, send them this way, hopefully I can save you a bit of trouble vocalising it :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Just add this button&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Just show this page&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Just update that view&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Just use facebook logins&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Just allow file uploads&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Just make it work on tablets&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;etc.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That word &amp;quot;just&amp;quot; makes my hairs stand on end - it trivialises the task before you&#39;ve had time to do investigate...&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Stone-Soup Software</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2013/04/24/stone-soup-software.html"/>
		<updated>2013-04-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2013/04/24/stone-soup-software</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Stone-Soup is a folk tale my Grandfather was fond of; it&#39;s about a cunning old lady who persuades a community to come together and make &amp;quot;stone soup&amp;quot;. It starts with a simple enough premise: she already has the magic stone, all she needs now is some hot water to make a hearty soup for all! Flabbergasted, the community agree to play along as it sounds too good to be true! After all, it&#39;s only a wee splash of hot water right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course adding a little salt &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; brings out the flavour of the stone. It&#39;s obvious. Some poor sap adds salt. And so it goes until pepper, potatoes, onions, mutton, carrots, split-peas, stock, turnips, celery, cream and barley are all added... the stone soup is truly wonderful! Who would have guessed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-MhwAdgI-_LI/Tnffqlo6VPI/AAAAAAAAAQc/H150h6Ii8ZM/s1600/stonesoup.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Stone-Soup&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No matter how fast paced life becomes, people are still people. In software terms the cunning old lady represents a client, the soup is the software, and the ingredients the features. And I hear stories like this all the time from my peers - hell, &lt;a href=&quot;/2011/09/09/2011-my-journey-so-far.html&quot;&gt;I&#39;ve been duped before&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way I see it: there are 2 types of cunning old lady to be wary of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Naive old ladies&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Truly believes hot water will turn her magic stone into soup! Her belief and passion is so strong that you might end up falliing for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;This type of client is either naive to the world of software or just plain ignorant of it. Having never pondered beyond the user-interface or basic concept she is blind to the time, forethought and plethora of decisions and hard work that goes into everything her UI or concept represents.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Not necessarily new to software - consider public sector workers with limited hands-on knowledge, accidental managers and all those &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codinghorror.com/blog/2006/07/separating-programming-sheep-from-non-programming-goats.html&quot;&gt;not-good software developers&lt;/a&gt; (sorry guys).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Deceptive old ladies&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carefully massages your expectations so that &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; believe water is all that is needed to make soup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;This type of client needs a big mind-map to keep track of their white-lies and half-truths. They know what they want and their machiavellian ways will make you their puppet.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Not necessarily software experts - be wary of anyone with arrogance or confidence in their profession; both traits are transferrable and if you let your guard down you could mistake them for inside knowledge and experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God forbid you ever meet some terrifying hybrid of both.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Linux Shell - Cheat Sheet</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2013/04/18/linux-shell-cheat-sheet.html"/>
		<updated>2013-04-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2013/04/18/linux-shell-cheat-sheet</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Quite honestly this is just a memory exercise before I start work today, how many of my favourite Linux commands can I splurge before 9am?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/High-level_programming_language&quot;&gt;High-Level-Programmer&lt;/a&gt; I don&#39;t do a great deal of work with threading, system processes or anything remotely concerned with system architecture - which is reflective of the kinds of shell commands I use on a day-to-day-basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;brush: bash&quot;&gt;
	#############
	## HISTORY ##
	#############

		# View shell history
		history

		# Search through shell history
		[CTRL]+[R]

	###########
	## FILES ##
	###########

		# Dump a file to the terminal in it&#39;s entirety
		cat &quot;/path/to/file&quot;

		# Read the first 10 lines of a file
		head -n 10 &quot;/path/to/file&quot;

		# Read the last 10 lines of a file
		tail -n 10 &quot;/path/to/file&quot;

		# Read the last 10 lines of a file AND follow it for changes
		tail -n 10 -f &quot;/path/to/log.txt&quot;

		# Read huge files in a lazy manner with keyboard scrolling
		less &quot;/path/to/file&quot;

		# Open a file with it&#39;s default application...
		# ...using a new thread so the shell isn&#39;t locked
			# XFCE
			setsid exo-open &quot;/path/to/file&quot;
			# Gnome
			setsid gnome-open &quot;/path/to/file&quot;

		# Recursively restore &quot;default&quot; CHMOD permissions for files and folders
		find &quot;/path/to/folder/&quot; -type d -print0 | xargs -0 chmod 755
		find &quot;/path/to/folder/&quot; -type f -print0 | xargs -0 chmod 644

	###################
	## FINDING STUFF ##
	###################

		# Locate files with an exact name, case-insensitive
		locate -i -b &#39;\avatar.png&#39;
		
		# Locate files using a regex pattern... ie:
			# ending with .png
			locate -r &#39;\.png$&#39;
			# ending with .png in a folder called &quot;img&quot;
			locate -r &#39;\/img\/.*\.png$&#39;

		# Using grep to narrow down a shell output
			# You need to know your ethernet Mac address so you type...
			ifconfig
			# ...but you&#39;re feeling lazy and don&#39;t want to read the whole thing!
			ifconfig | grep -i ethernet
			# Or you need to quickly find a particular error in your server logs
			grep -i &quot;file does not exist&quot; &quot;/path/to/log.txt&quot;

		# Finding the full path to a command
		whereis cat
		whereis less
		whereis whereis # This command tells you the path of the command that tells you the path of a command...
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully there&#39;s something interesting there, if not, why not?&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>GViz Mister! Embeddable graphViz</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2013/04/12/gviz-mister-embeddable-graphviz-charts.html"/>
		<updated>2013-04-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2013/04/12/gviz-mister-embeddable-graphviz-charts</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As a visual thinker I always keep at hand a scrapbook, notepad or whiteboard covered in diagrams of various design; my favourite being flowcharts and spider diagrams. I find it very easy to group similar concepts or dependencies by visualising my scribblings, I can still picture a valuable diagram that has long been tossed in the paperbasket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve recently become a &lt;strong&gt;big&lt;/strong&gt; fan of &lt;a href=&quot;http://graphviz.org/&quot;&gt;graphViz&lt;/a&gt;, a program that allows you to create &amp;quot;graphs&amp;quot; by defining the connections between nodes. It&#39;s a splendid piece of kit that is childs play to use, for example this diagram...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;script type=&quot;gviz&quot; data-layout=&quot;dot&quot;&gt;&lt;![CDATA[
		digraph G {
			graph [
				truecolor=true
				bgcolor=&quot;#FFFFFF00&quot;
			];
			node [
				shape=box
				style=filled
				fillcolor=&quot;#FFFFFF&quot;
				fontcolor=&quot;#0F192A&quot;
			];
			david -&gt; notepad -&gt; offline;
			david -&gt; scrapbook -&gt; offline;
			david -&gt; whiteboard -&gt; offline;
			david -&gt; graphviz -&gt; online;
		}
	]]&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...is trivial to describe using the graphviz language, the layout and format is automatically calculated for you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;brush: xml&quot;&gt;
	digraph G {
		david -&gt; notepad -&gt; offline;
		david -&gt; scrapbook -&gt; offline;
		david -&gt; whiteboard -&gt; offline;
		david -&gt; graphviz -&gt; online;
	}
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Let&#39;s make that embeddable...&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Normally you would have to fire up the command-line and run graphviz to convert your definition into an image to then view, however I&#39;ve found these diagrams to be a critical part of my toolbox and have created an online webservice that allows them to be embedded directly into a webpage. No more command-line needed, just instant gratification!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Head over to my &lt;a href=&quot;/gviz/&quot;&gt;GViz documentation&lt;/a&gt; page to see how to embed graphs directly on your webpage...&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Convert From Tumblr to Jekyll Using PHP</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2013/04/09/convert-from-tumblr-to-jekyll-using-php.html"/>
		<updated>2013-04-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2013/04/09/convert-from-tumblr-to-jekyll-using-php</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As you know I&#39;ve recently upgraded my site to use github&#39;s &amp;quot;Jekyll pages&amp;quot;, a big reason for the move was to migrate my more active tumblr to my less active personal site. Mostly to drive traffic directly here in order to promote my other work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having tinkered with the Tumblr API I know that it would be really easy to loop my blog articles and dump out Jekyll formatted posts. There were various ruby gems available that claimed to work, but this being my first foray into ruby I kept encountering dependency errors; long-story-short I decided to just smash out a PHP script to the same effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PHP script to convert tumblr blog articles to jekyll posts, modify the settings then simply run this in your terminal: &lt;strong&gt;php tumblr2jekyll.php&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/oodavid/5344381&quot;&gt;tumblr2jekyll.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;https://gist.github.com/oodavid/5344381.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>oodavid.com is now Jekyll powered</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2013/04/08/oodavidcom-is-now-jekyll-powered.html"/>
		<updated>2013-04-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2013/04/08/oodavidcom-is-now-jekyll-powered</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Good programmers are always itchy to learn something new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week I decided it was time to give oodavid.com a bit of a dusting - I used this as an excuse to learn how to use &lt;a href=&quot;http://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;github pages&lt;/a&gt; and the splendid Jekyll system that is available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://octodex.github.com/images/chellocat.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; HEIGHT=&quot;300&quot; alt=&quot;Github Octocat - portal edition&quot;&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;A bit like Portal, run your code through Jekyll and out pops a proper website! Magic.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process has been fun and straightforward:
&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;install ruby&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;install the jekyll gem (and some dependencies)&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;setup a folder hierarchy&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;make some header and footer HTML snippets&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;make some templates (blog and homepage)&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;test it locally using the jekyll server&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;push to github&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;rejoice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s no point in writing up a tutorial since &lt;a href=&quot;http://brianscaturro.com/2012/06/12/blog-with-jekyll-and-github.html&quot;&gt;Brian Scaturro&lt;/a&gt; has done such a good job!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did however write a simple PHP script to port over all my Tumblr posts into the Jekyll format. I&#39;ll write that up in the next post!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>My new Office, thanks to Ignite100</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2013/04/02/my-new-office-thanks-to-ignite100.html"/>
		<updated>2013-04-02T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2013/04/02/my-new-office-thanks-to-ignite100</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Working at home is a mix of awesome and loathsome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On the plus side&lt;/strong&gt; there is no commute, I can cook anything I like for lunch &lt;em&gt;(a massive bonus for me)&lt;/em&gt;, I have peace and quiet, my office toys (projector, sound-system, whiteboard etc) get to be my cinema and party-fodder and my actual toys (mostly nerf guns and puzzles) get to be my distraction while &amp;quot;compiling&amp;quot;...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img alt=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;http://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/compiling.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Negatively speaking&lt;/strong&gt; you find yourself cracking at the seams for want of good company, even for just a bit of lunchtime craic, there&#39;s also the astronomical utility bills and the fact that my lunchtime would regularly drag on for 2 hours - &lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;I started early this morning and will make up for it this evening, I can justify a couple of episodes of X-Files with my lunch.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt; Again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it was this shitty extended winter that did it, but I decided to fire off a tweet &lt;span&gt;for a desk to rent and received a &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;very&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; swift reply from &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/paul_a_smith&quot;&gt;Paul Smith&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt; - why yes, I &lt;em&gt;would&lt;/em&gt; like to take the last remaining desk in an office full of people I know and admire.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ignite100.com/&quot;&gt;Ignite100&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt; office is a splendid space in central Newcastle; it houses startup companies on their &lt;/span&gt;accelerator&lt;span&gt; program. Successful companies are encouraged to stay in the area and rent space from Ignite. The end result is an ever growing community of likeminded, driven people. They also rent a few desks, boon to me!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Ignite100&#39;s business model is simple and exciting, when the penny dropped I felt awed. By keeping hold of these successful businesses they are creating a sort of economical critical mass, and like any large body it will only serve to pull in more and more businesses. Good for their books, good for the region, and good for lonely nerds like me.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>My weekend project - Molecule Match</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2013/03/26/my-weekend-project-molecule-match.html"/>
		<updated>2013-03-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2013/03/26/my-weekend-project-molecule-match</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I like games, but I rarely get the chance to play them. My favourite are games that are hard, like &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;reeaally&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; hard, that make you think, that make you hurt. In business terms it&#39;s a terrible idea to ostracise your target audience to any degree, as such these games are a rare beast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the start of the year I found myself yearning to get back to my codey roots and have a tinker with games, I spent a lazy Sunday writing and doodling about the various half-baked ideas that I&#39;ve had over the years and finally remembered a game that we played as kids called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sAhLKcuKO1s&quot; title=&quot;Chiral Gameplay&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Chiral&lt;/a&gt;, man that game ticked all my boxes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the style of a man that has a 1001 things to do I started tinkering anyhow...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;iframe width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;435&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/vBg50OvoVvA?vq=hd720&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;How apt.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thusfar I have created:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;A decoupled &amp;quot;grid engine&amp;quot; to power any number of games on grids&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;A proof-of-concept implementation that presents a grid of atoms, each has a random valency and can be connected to create molecules.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;A simple scoring engine that rewards massive molecules&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Some intro levels that explain how to play the game (not shown in the video)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I plan to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Design some different game-modes; timed, clear the board, &amp;quot;match 3 style&amp;quot; (where more atoms drop down when cleared etc), puzzle&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Make the intro levels work really well&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Get some music made for it - probably by &lt;a href=&quot;http://echolevel.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Brendan Ratliff&lt;/a&gt;, possibly in the style of &lt;a href=&quot;http://youarelistening.to/deepthought&quot;&gt;You Are Listening to... Deep Thought&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Make some sexy visuals / animations - &lt;em&gt;I find this quite daunting&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Reprogram it for Android (native) and iPhone (native) -&lt;em&gt; it&#39;s currently just Javascript&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh yeah, and make it REALLY SWEARY. I don&#39;t know why, but I like the idea of having the avatar being frustrated by the game and pouring out a constant torrent of abuse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Molecule? Bollecule!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>OOP - Method Bubbling in PHP</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2013/03/19/oop-method-bubbling-in-php.html"/>
		<updated>2013-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2013/03/19/oop-method-bubbling-in-php</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Contrary to my online handle &lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;Object-Oriented David&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt; I use Object-Oriented Programming very sparingly. I &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; however try to use the right tool for the job and take on as many of the concepts that I love about frameworks and libraries I admire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In creating a &amp;quot;query builder&amp;quot; for the NexGen platform I ended up wanting to use syntax that I would associate with jQuery; chained and namespaced with a common bubbling of methods and properties. Thus I designed a very simple class (it&#39;s simple, but it took me about 2 hours of experimentation to make!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here&#39;s the code - with example&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/oodavid/5195592&quot;&gt;https://gist.github.com/oodavid/5195592&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my implementation you can run queries like these:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;brush: php;&quot;&gt;query-&amp;gt;sql(&#39;SELECT TABLES&#39;)-&amp;gt;execute()-&amp;gt;debug();
query-&amp;gt;select(&#39;*&#39;)-&amp;gt;from(&#39;users&#39;)-&amp;gt;join(&#39;avatar&#39;)-&amp;gt;where(&#39;id&#39;, 1)-&amp;gt;limit(1)-&amp;gt;execute()-&amp;gt;debug();
query-&amp;gt;delete()-&amp;gt;from(&#39;users&#39;)-&amp;gt;where(&#39;id&#39;, 10)-&amp;gt;limit(1)-&amp;gt;execute()-&amp;gt;debug();
query-&amp;gt;upsert(&#39;users&#39;)-&amp;gt;data(array( &#39;id&#39;=&amp;gt;NULL, &#39;email&#39;=&amp;gt;&#39;david@oodavid.com&#39; ))-&amp;gt;return(TRUE)-&amp;gt;execute()-&amp;gt;debug();&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;As you can see, each use execute() and debug(), lets explain what happens:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;execute()&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;...is defined on the child objects sql, select, upsert and delete&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;They each build a SQL variable and store it as a property on the parent query object.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;They also access the parents database handler and execute the query.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;debug()&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;...is NOT defined on any of the child objects, thus the method bubbles up to the parent query object.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Since the child-&amp;gt;execute() methods set the SQL property on the parent, this common method runs an analysis of the query showing timings, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;bottlenecks and other useful information&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>A Server Monitor that Doesn't Suck - End Result</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2013/03/13/a-server-monitor-that-doesnt-suck.html"/>
		<updated>2013-03-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2013/03/13/a-server-monitor-that-doesnt-suck</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;To follow on from the last post - on Friday I quickly cobbled together a simple server monitor that I&#39;m proud to show off, it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Looks good full-screen&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Shows a single metric at a time&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Slowly fades between metrics&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Highlights the severity in a way I can see in my peripheral&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Works on mobile devices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I&#39;ve only 7 metrics up and running the basics are in place so I&#39;ll slowly add in new metrics until I&#39;ve got a complete view of the business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img alt=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/ff97247a98714dd6a06700d7c738ff81/tumblr_inline_mjlf8kiPUA1qz4rgp.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;running on my local machine and scanning my media disk&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img alt=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/3ac29bbcec295ecea0ca438b02a21d8b/tumblr_inline_mjlf8zYGas1qz4rgp.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;a useful business metric, these 2 people could represent money&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img alt=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/f0450eaae03a28a810e03792dfaee50c/tumblr_inline_mjlf98OFlE1qz4rgp.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;click anywhere on the screen to drill down&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img alt=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/1c4f555e15290240d49504f9582ae637/tumblr_inline_mjlf9tcUtG1qz4rgp.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;there&#39;s a few vanity metrics - to keep me happy and impress visitors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So there you have it, a server monitor that doesn&#39;t suck.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>A Server Monitor that doesn't explode your eyeballs</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2013/03/07/a-server-monitor-that-doesnt-explode-your-eyeballs.html"/>
		<updated>2013-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2013/03/07/a-server-monitor-that-doesnt-explode-your-eyeballs</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been looking forward to the final item on my weekly todo, so much so that all other items have been completed with gusto! Time to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Write a server monitor that looks effing awesome&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rationale behind this tangential quest is that while playing with &lt;a href=&quot;http://nagios.org&quot; title=&quot;The Industry Standard IT Monitor&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;nagios&lt;/a&gt; I can&#39;t help but think that, while functionally useful it&#39;s visually unappealing - viz. I will never look at it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img alt=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/fd66155fc900c304036e27a47acc35be/tumblr_inline_mjadzxvFtM1qz4rgp.png&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;The Industry Standard - a bit ugly!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Y&#39;see, I&#39;m used to using things like &lt;a href=&quot;http://conky.sourceforge.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;conky&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Conky is lightweight linux program that renders an overlay on your desktop background image, mine&#39;s configured to show system errors, new emails, CPU usage, network load and various system variables. It&#39;s super handy because it&#39;s just always there. LIVE Errors are most important, thus I make them really pop out at me:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img alt=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/fceb9a6c500924693f5e8921a8591afa/tumblr_inline_mjaeg68R3r1qz4rgp.png&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Visually nicer, but limited in functionality&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So my plan is to combine the functionality of nagios, the simplicity of conky with a few ideas I have rattling around... &lt;span&gt;I want:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;A system monitor that is always visible&lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt; - a wall-mounted display&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;That requires no interaction&lt;strong&gt; - until I need to dig deeper&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;That I can access from anywhere&lt;strong&gt; - on the www&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;That is chunky and obvious from afar&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;That is visually appealing&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;That shows me everything I need to know&lt;strong&gt; - including business metrics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I already have a number of scripts and programs that help me get notified of errors / hiccups / statistics etc but they&#39;re all so very disparate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is with these things in mind that I am dedicating the next few days to create a basic prototype that doesn&#39;t suck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a nutshell:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;A chunky interface that cycles through core metrics and statistics, slowing down on views with errors.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s going to be a lot of fun in making:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;http://getspringy.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;force-directed graph&lt;/a&gt; that represents my database&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;A grid of recently processed images&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Topline database statistics&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Recent server errors - as chunky as all hell&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.soleilnoir.net/believein/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Inspired by something beautiful&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wish me luck!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>When you *have* to install all the Internet Explorers, do it in a one-liner</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2013/02/08/when-you-have-to-install-all-the-internet-explorers.html"/>
		<updated>2013-02-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2013/02/08/when-you-have-to-install-all-the-internet-explorers</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;You know how it is, you make something awesome for a company, they all use modern browsers, but their customers? Oh, they&#39;re still rocking IE6 and 7. I quite honestly thought those days were long behind us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, they may seem like dark dark days, but at least we&#39;re not alone - with the advent and growing popularity of github and general open-sourcery I managed to find this GEM of a repository:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/xdissent/ievms&quot;&gt;https://github.com/xdissent/ievms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quite simply, if you have Orcale VirtualBox installed you can download and install all the IE&#39;s in a command-line onner:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;curl -s &lt;a href=&quot;https://raw.github.com/xdissent/ievms/master/ievms.sh&quot;&gt;https://raw.github.com/xdissent/ievms/master/ievms.sh&lt;/a&gt; | bash&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isn&#39;t it beautiful?&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Inspired by MailChimp: No more social Logins</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2012/10/30/inspired-by-mailchimp-no-more-social-logins.html"/>
		<updated>2012-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2012/10/30/inspired-by-mailchimp-no-more-social-logins</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We&#39;d been A-B testing a new &amp;quot;login with Facebook&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;login with Twitter&amp;quot; links alongside the regular email and password form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Group A - Half of our users see the normal register and login with email option&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Group B - This half &lt;strong&gt;also&lt;/strong&gt; see the extra login / registration options&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We noticed that Group B (those with &lt;strong&gt;three&lt;/strong&gt; login choices) were having increased login failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a little research we came across an astounding article from MailChimp covering this exact scenario, I&#39;d be foolish to think I could express this problem nearly as well as these guys, suffice to say that we&#39;ve came to the same conclusion... an excellent (if a little lengthy) read:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;blog.mailchimp.com/social-login-buttons-arent-worth-it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>One awesome personal finances spreadsheet</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2012/08/09/one-awesome-personal-finances-spreadsheet.html"/>
		<updated>2012-08-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2012/08/09/one-awesome-personal-finances-spreadsheet</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Having been involved with a number of &amp;quot;bootstraps&amp;quot; &lt;em&gt;(4 in a row!)&lt;/em&gt; I found myself struggling a little with my personal cashflow... cash&lt;strong&gt;flaw&lt;/strong&gt; might be a more appropriate name TBH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So anyhow; last year after a joyous debacle I decided that it was pertinent that I took the bull by the horns and really get to know just how these things work. Today I find myself more than comfortable with finances from the personal level all the way to large-company level &lt;em&gt;(double-entry basics, debit, credit, invoices, credit-notes, credit-ratings, credit-insurers yada yada)&lt;/em&gt; and today I would like to share with you a pretty powerful spreadsheet that I use to analyse my personal bank account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://oodavid.com/finances/template.ods&quot;&gt;http://oodavid.com/finances/template.ods&lt;/a&gt; - designed for &lt;strong&gt;Open Office&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;sorry Excel users, but it probably doesn&#39;t work! Feel free to port it :-)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s been tweaked and tinkered with and I think I&#39;m finally happy with it. It&#39;s designed to be a no-brainer to user:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Paste in your bank statement at the end of each month&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Assign each transaction a category&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Magic happens&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are 14 tabs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About&lt;/strong&gt; - this explains how it works and allows you to set some variables that affect the way the thing works&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Money&lt;/strong&gt; - this is your balance sheet if you will, or a summary of your monthly spendings and earnings with opening balance, closing balance and a grouping of how you spend your cash&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;April &amp;gt; February&lt;/strong&gt; - this is where you paste your bank-statements then categorise each transaction, once you&#39;ve done that the &lt;strong&gt;Money&lt;/strong&gt; tab is automagically updated!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://oodavid.com/finances/screenshot.png&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m8hykvcDEW1qk6dpq.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;by selecting the category the transaction is added to the correct month / category cell on the &lt;strong&gt;Money&lt;/strong&gt; tab (click for a bigger image)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So every month I paste in my statement, categorise each item &lt;em&gt;(about 60 on average)&lt;/em&gt; and then I have a number of useful things in my possession:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;An exact breakdown of how much I&#39;m spending and earning in different areas (groceries, clothes, electronics etc).&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;An intimate knowledge of my money. Quite a handy thing when you want to budget etc.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Proof. Just in-case the taxman or some other arsehole needs it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please download it and have a tinker, if I make your life a teeny tiny bit better just give me some love and we&#39;re even :-)&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>1DayLater is evolving...</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2012/07/17/1daylater-is-evolving.html"/>
		<updated>2012-07-17T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2012/07/17/1daylater-is-evolving</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For the past year or so we have been working on building a new 1DayLater from the ground and I&#39;m letting myself get excited about it; this blog post is clearly premature, but what the hey, I want to write a little about what we&#39;re doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://new.1daylater.com/&quot;&gt;http://new.1daylater.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; - our holding page, isn&#39;t it nice?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m79oy4O9Y11qk6dpq.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image showing the evolution of man from amoeba&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;your 1DayLater is evolving...&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technology Wise&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The easiest changes to describe are our technologies, almost every choice made in the original system has been reviewed and (mostly) found wanting. We&#39;ve really matured the software with this new version and myself as a programmer too; I&#39;m growing ever more comfortable with the iterative development process to the point that I consider a bad day as NOT pushing a new release live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of this has come from building the NexGen software with Lucion Environmental &lt;em&gt;(more on this another time)&lt;/em&gt; suffice to say that when you support a diverse and growing company you see the fruits of your labour almost instantly. If the person in the room next door has a bug and they see it fixed instantly there&#39;s gratitude aplenty!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I digress, here&#39;s some of the changes we&#39;ve made on the new 1DayLater... and why&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Version Control&lt;/strong&gt;: Subversion &amp;gt; Git&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;once you get over the initial learning curve, git has many advantages&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deployment&lt;/strong&gt;: FTP &amp;gt; Git Hooks&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;we can update the site with simply &amp;quot;git push&amp;quot; and all the right files will be in place&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hosting&lt;/strong&gt;: Rackspace &amp;gt; Amazon Web Services&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;an excellent developer community and lower price makes this logical&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Database&lt;/strong&gt;: MyISAM &amp;gt; InnoDB&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;currently 1DayLater is non-relational, we now require a more logical relational structure&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Markup&lt;/strong&gt;: Handcoded &amp;gt; Twitter Bootstrap&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;frankly, I can&#39;t afford to spend too much time pushing pixels - this makes it much quicker to knock up pages&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Templating&lt;/strong&gt;: Custom &amp;gt; Handlebars&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;I wrote my own templating engine and it was very patchy, we picked the most popular and active engine for the new system&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PDF Printing&lt;/strong&gt;: wkhtmltopdf &amp;gt; PrinceXML&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;once we go live we will (gulp) fork out the licence fee for a commercial printing program; after all this will be our new product&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Product Wise&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://new.1daylater.com/&quot;&gt;http://new.1daylater.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; - the holding page should explain it nicely, with pictures and all!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But if you prefer I can quickly explain what we&#39;re making:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Our &lt;strong&gt;Users&lt;/strong&gt; can create &lt;strong&gt;Quotes&lt;/strong&gt; to send to their clients&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quotes&lt;/strong&gt; are made up of &lt;strong&gt;Line-Items&lt;/strong&gt; with an estimate tally&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Users&lt;/strong&gt; can then &lt;strong&gt;Log their Activity&lt;/strong&gt; against these Line-Items&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;They can then convert their Activity into &lt;strong&gt;Invoices &lt;/strong&gt;to send to their clients&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Tony the plasterer Quotes for a small Job&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;It is made up of these Line-Items
		&lt;ul&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;3 Days on site at £250 / day&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;1 Disposable tarpaulin at £30&lt;em&gt; (estimated)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;1 Day of Van hire at £60&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;On site he logs his work against these activities, on the second day he notices his client has torn the tarpaulin so he gets another one and so logs two of that&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;He can then draw up an Invoice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea is that Tony does the MINIMUM amount of admin but gets access to some &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;very&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; valuable information and tools, ie:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Send Invoices and Quotes to his clients&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Get notified when his clients view his Invoices and Quotes&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Find the Quotes with outstanding work (ie money)&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;See which Invoices are overdue&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Visualise his profitability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore he can inviate collaborators to log their activities against his Quotes (maybe he hires staff etc.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Business Wise&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, we&#39;ve paid off the business loan, we&#39;re financially stable (profitable in fact) and are busy investing in the company. On the financial front we&#39;re pretty happy at the moment but (as all businesses should) we want to be &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;very&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; profitable and hire more staff for support and whatnot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the new product we spent a great deal of time pondering how to price the product and catch customers at each stage of the curve, this is what we thought:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When is the product valuable?&lt;/strong&gt;
		&lt;ul&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;When the client sends an Invoice&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;we thought that the data, visuals, outstanding work etc were valuable, but that they&#39;re also so intangible that would be difficult to describe and sell&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How much is an Invoice worth?&lt;/strong&gt;
		&lt;ul&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;ONE POUND&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;We decided that it couldn&#39;t impact on the value of the invoice but had to be a nice round number, a QUID seems decent. We&#39;ll review this soon enough&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How can our users pay for it?&lt;/strong&gt;
		&lt;ul&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;On a subscription (Monthly or Yearly)&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;Buy a set number of Invoices (Tokens)&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last time round the finances were second to the product, this time we&#39;ve actually gone ahead and designed and implemented our payment pages first. Yup, before the product is even finished; we don&#39;t want bugfixes and whatnot getting in the way of our cashflow, after all if 1DayLater wasn&#39;t financially viable (for us) those bugfixes and improvements would be worthless as the service would eventually disappear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lessons have been learned. I am excited.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>I'm delighted to announce...</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2012/06/04/im-delighted-to-announce.html"/>
		<updated>2012-06-04T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2012/06/04/im-delighted-to-announce</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For the past 8 months I have been working on a contract with one of the country&#39;s finest Asbestos Surveying companies &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lucion.co.uk/&quot; title=&quot;Lucion&quot;&gt;Lucion Environmental&lt;/a&gt;, developing &amp;quot;NexGen&amp;quot;; an online platform to service their entire company from quoting to site-work, report generation and finally invoices... and then some in-between.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just last week I managed to &amp;quot;upgrade&amp;quot; my contract to the golden-egg of working arrangements - permanent work as a consultant developer! This means that I&#39;m afforded all the luxuries of self-employment with the added bonus of financial stability for the foreseeable future!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now... some things&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What has made this project different?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most exciting thing about working with an established business is that their procedures, company structure and needs are already well defined and instantly available to me. I&#39;ve not once thought to myself &amp;quot;this is an interesting feature, I hope it&#39;s right&amp;quot; instead I just need to express my ideas to the right person(s) and they tell me straight. In fact I spent most of my first month (or two) doing just this - building a picture in my mind of the company as a single coherent thought; it&#39;s now so familiar to me that I&#39;m confidently autonomous in my work. LOVE IT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you&#39;re a consultant developer, who&#39;s your boss?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I imagine there are 123 bosses, so in no particular order:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;120 Staff Members&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt; - that probably makes me the company bitch&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Patrick Morton&lt;/strong&gt; - Director, instigator of NexGen&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Me&lt;/strong&gt; - some ideas are too good not to act on, brownie points live here&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Data&lt;/strong&gt; - if the data says &amp;quot;help me&amp;quot;, I oblige&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve noticed something interesting with this setup, If you pick out ANYONE from the list and focus solely on making their life easier / happier / better in any way you can, they become more likely to engage with the product - often with so much energy that it infects the people around them. Probably a valuable observation when instigating massive change in such a large company; I bet that&#39;s how the fashion companies work it: target the alpha males / females and make them happy, then everyone else follows suit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What&#39;s next?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, we&#39;ve already seen a gradual rollout in the Northern office, and next week we&#39;re going live with the remaining 6 regional offices; this entails a meeting of the managers, Directors and myself... I just &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; it will be like when Mafia bosses meet in the movies; all suits, meatballs and gesticulations. It&#39;ll be awesome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that I have a &amp;quot;development backlog&amp;quot; that represents months of solid work; everything from platform engineering, scalability, feature requests, bugfixes and a few things that I&#39;m confident are going to make the competition weep with envy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anything else?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Me and Paul have been &lt;a href=&quot;http://new.1daylater.com/&quot; title=&quot;New 1DayLater&quot;&gt;rebooting 1DayLater&lt;/a&gt; with a focus on helping freelancers and businesses &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; make money and being contractually watertight. Watch this space&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Who's a Git?</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2012/05/10/whos-a-git.html"/>
		<updated>2012-05-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2012/05/10/whos-a-git</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m3tic8wiH81qk6dpq.png&quot; alt=&quot;git shell showing a single branch being used for everything&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;8 months ago I didn&#39;t really *do* branching&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m3ticoMYJJ1qk6dpq.png&quot; alt=&quot;git shell showing branches being used in earnest&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;now it&#39;s all I do&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Linux Screencasting with recordmydesktop</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2012/05/07/linux-screencasting-with-recordmydesktop.html"/>
		<updated>2012-05-07T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2012/05/07/linux-screencasting-with-recordmydesktop</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have today encountered an item on my todo list &lt;em&gt;(the list is so long I can&#39;t actually remember writing this item... madness!)&lt;/em&gt; - which is to record a set of tutorial screencasts for a SaaS that I am developing - quicker than writing help-documents and probably a bit more fun. Something I&#39;ve been meaning to try my hand at for a long time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So there was a little chinstroking and headscratching trying to get this setup to my liking - I encountered some common linux audio problems like static / whitenoise on my mic etc. but in the end the steps to get setup were pretty straightforward; install some apps, set some settings and off we go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The scenario&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Ubuntu Linux 12.10 (running XFCE)&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;PulseAudio&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;A USB Mic that works well with Skype&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Record screencasts of my desktop&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Capture my crisp sounding USB Mic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Software Choices&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried a &lt;strong&gt;lot&lt;/strong&gt; of different programs, some with fancy GUIs, old ones, news ones, VLC had a lookin but in the end these are the programs I like best - they&#39;re snappy, simple (or no) interface, and they each &amp;quot;just work&amp;quot; without extra bloat:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;recordmydesktop&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; - command-line screencapturing (very smart)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gtk-recordmydesktop&lt;/strong&gt; - a &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; simple GUI for the above&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pavucontrol&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; - &amp;quot;advanced&amp;quot; pulse audio GUI&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To install:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;brush: bash;&quot;&gt;sudo apt-get install recordmydesktop gtk-recordmydesktop pavucontrol&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Setup&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will address this part... WITH A SCREENCAST!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;iframe width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;435&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/SvdljjkLB8w?vq=hd720&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;How apt.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I had to wade through quite a few guides, videos and manpages, these were the only guides I needed in the end:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://help.ubuntu.com/community/SkypeTroubleshooting&quot;&gt;https://help.ubuntu.com/community/SkypeTroubleshooting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;shows how to select a microphone device with pavucontrol&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sN10CXyOC0E&quot;&gt;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sN10CXyOC0E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;shows to set your sound device to &amp;quot;pulse&amp;quot; on recordmydesktop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Redshift your computer monitor. For the Zzzz...</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2012/04/21/redshift-your-computer-monitor-for-the-zzzz.html"/>
		<updated>2012-04-21T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2012/04/21/redshift-your-computer-monitor-for-the-zzzz</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have recently discovered a neat little package for linux called &amp;quot;Redshift&amp;quot;; so simple and elegant and very worthy of a mention on the blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;http://jonls.dk/wp-content/uploads/redshift-icon-256-150x150.png&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; alt=&quot;Redshift icon: A red light bulb&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jonls.dk/redshift/&quot;&gt;http://jonls.dk/redshift/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; - cheers Jon Lund Steffensen!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once installed and running at startup, redshift adjusts your monitor(s) colour &amp;quot;temperature&amp;quot; to match the time of day / year and local weather conditions. With all these modern gadgets bombarding our eyes it&#39;s no wonder sleep is &lt;a href=&quot;http://articles.cnn.com/2010-05-13/tech/sleep.gadgets.ipad_1_ipad-sleep-disorders-e-book?_s=PM:TECH&quot;&gt;becoming&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://healthland.time.com/2011/06/27/tv-video-games-at-night-may-cause-sleep-problems-in-kids/&quot;&gt;a&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.webmd.com/sleep-disorders/news/20030620/nighttime-computer-users-may-lose-sleep&quot;&gt;big&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://imogen-wright.suite101.com/insomnia-linked-to-pc-use-a237276&quot;&gt;problem&lt;/a&gt;; this wee helper acts as a great cue that it&#39;s time to shutdown and get some shuteye.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And on that note... Zzzz...&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Automatically backup MySQL to Amazon S3 (and a dog)</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2012/03/26/automatically-backup-mysql-to-amazon-s3-and-a-dog.html"/>
		<updated>2012-03-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2012/03/26/automatically-backup-mysql-to-amazon-s3-and-a-dog</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been revisiting my backup scripts today and I decided to publish my notes on how to backup your MySQL databases to Amazon S3 - I forgot just how simple it was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Install s3cmd&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Write a bash script that...
		&lt;ul&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;lists your databases&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;dumps them to a temporary file&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;uploads them to s3&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;deletes the temporary file&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Run it with cron every night&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;The full instructions are here:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/2206527&quot;&gt;https://gist.github.com/2206527&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m1i5hmW6Qu1qk6dpq.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;and a dog...!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&#39;m gonna meet this pup at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nessr.net/node/73&quot; title=&quot;North East Springer Spaniel Rescue&quot;&gt;the NESSR Easter Event&lt;/a&gt; next weekend&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Refactoring an old database for multilang support</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2012/03/14/refactoring-an-old-database-for-multilang-support.html"/>
		<updated>2012-03-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2012/03/14/refactoring-an-old-database-for-multilang-support</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve recently had the opportunity to revisit and re-factor a database that I wrote designed a decade ago; it&#39;s still up-and-running with heavy traffic however it&#39;s become difficult for the current developer to maintain &lt;em&gt;(hey Dad)&lt;/em&gt; and the client is looking to add a multi-language slant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m0vio9duHD1qk6dpq.png&quot; alt=&quot;EER diagram showing non-relational database with no scope for i18n support&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;the old, non-relational database&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m0vio12Oju1qk6dpq.png&quot; alt=&quot;Refactored EER diagram showing fully-relational database with scope for i18n support&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;the new relational database + multilang translations&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Table-wise we decided to keep with pretty much the same to make the transition painless, however when you compare the original and the new you can see everything has more structure and logic:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Converted from MyISAM to InnoDB&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;the new MySQL standard&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Foreign-Keys have been added&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Additional Unique indexes for structural integrity&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Split the content into
		&lt;ul&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;Structural tables&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;Content tables (for multi-lang)&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m0vke31FY41qk6dpq.png&quot; alt=&quot;Simplified EER to show only the i18n parts of the diagram&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;structure on the top, content on the bottom&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this structure we can do some pretty nifty queries that pull out the language of choice but fall-back to English on a &lt;strong&gt;per-column-basis&lt;/strong&gt;, observe:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;brush: sql;&quot;&gt;SELECT
	u.id,
	COALESCE(lang1.title,     lang2.title)      AS title,
	COALESCE(lang1.body,      lang2.body)       AS body,
	COALESCE(lang1.voiceover, lang2.voiceover)  AS voiceover,
	COALESCE(lang1.handout,   lang2.handout)    AS handout
FROM `units` AS u
	LEFT JOIN units_lang AS lang1 ON lang1.unit = u.id AND lang1.lang = &#39;zh&#39;
	LEFT JOIN units_lang AS lang2 ON lang2.unit = u.id AND lang2.lang = &#39;en&#39;
WHERE u.id = 32;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this statement:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;u&lt;/strong&gt; is the structural &lt;strong&gt;units&lt;/strong&gt; table with common info (only id in this case)&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lang1&lt;/strong&gt; is the multilang table &lt;strong&gt;units_lang&lt;/strong&gt; in Chinese (zh)&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lang2&lt;/strong&gt; is the multilang table &lt;strong&gt;units_lang&lt;/strong&gt; in English (en)&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;COALESCE&lt;/strong&gt;picks out the first NON-NULL column, so these go:
		&lt;ul&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;Chinese table&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;then&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;English table&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pretty nifty huh?&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>A nice search solution and interface :-)</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2012/02/16/a-nice-search-solution-and-interface.html"/>
		<updated>2012-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2012/02/16/a-nice-search-solution-and-interface</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You&#39;ll probably get lost in this post. I should doodle a diagram... Apologies.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So today I&#39;ve tasked myself with improving the search feature on the NexGen project (itself a post for another day), the scenario is this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;A Company has Contracts&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Contracts are linked to Accounts and Primary Contacts&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Contracts are made up of Jobs&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;There may be hundreds or thousands of Jobs in the case of rolling contracts&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Jobs are linked to Sites and various other bits and bobs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The search should allow you to get you from the homepage to the exact piece of information you need based on the information at hand - you might have a Site Address, Client Name, Reference ID etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The search itself is fully functional, however I&#39;ve not been 100% happy with the interface - &lt;em&gt;until today!&lt;/em&gt; The old interface was pretty bog standard:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Show a list of results that match the search criteria&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Don&#39;t show results that don&#39;t match the search criteria&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pretty simple right? Indeed, but the interface actually requires MORE components:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lets say we searched for the Site: &amp;quot;Durham Castle&amp;quot; - it&#39;s used by 2 Jobs within a single Contract. That Contract has other Jobs at different sites. If we only show those two Jobs then how do we see the other Jobs? We need:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;A show-all Jobs button&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not so bad right? Well, I think it is awful - the interface bit is OK, the coding bit is OK, but the users of the system have to be aware that &amp;quot;we&#39;re only showing the Jobs that match your search&amp;quot; - it might not be obvious that there&#39;s other Jobs in that Contract!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So my solution is to show all the Jobs (well, paginated) but with the search results at the top. In the prime spot :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;brush: sql;&quot;&gt;SELECT * FROM `jobs` ORDER BY site=22 DESC, id ASC;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m really happy with this one even if you don&#39;t get it.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Deploying with Git(HUB)</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2012/02/12/deploying-with-git-hub.html"/>
		<updated>2012-02-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2012/02/12/deploying-with-git-hub</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The last post about deployment was good, but I ran into a few problems to do with submodules. I am developing 3 web-apps in parallel that all use common code, so in keeping with DRY methodology the apps simply link to submodules in order to share code. With the technique outlined in the previous post submodules were not automatically updated; making it all but useless for my needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So today I have quickly researched and utilised an alternative - using github features to trigger automatic deployment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In keeping with trendy trends, here&#39;s the &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/1809044&quot; title=&quot;Auto-deploy with php and git(hub) on an EC2 Amazon AMI&quot;&gt;GIST on GitHub&lt;/a&gt; - you can see that I have forked a very good gist and there&#39;s a few references in the post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a pretty nice announcement with-regard-to my worklife to make soon, but need to wait till everything is confirmed before I do. Happy times my friends :-)&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Deploying with Git > handy hints</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2012/01/30/deploying-with-git-handy-hints.html"/>
		<updated>2012-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2012/01/30/deploying-with-git-handy-hints</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;With regards to deploying your site with git, there&#39;s some potentially confusing posts out there; a quick google for &amp;quot;git deployment&amp;quot; will turn up a few (seemingly) outdated posts (I&#39;m using &lt;strong&gt;git version 1.7.4.1&lt;/strong&gt; at the time of writing), ie:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;a href=&quot;http://ryanflorence.com/simple-git-deployment/&quot;&gt;http://ryanflorence.com/simple-git-deployment/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
		&lt;em&gt;I had a few problems with this one when I got to the push stage, apparently this occurs with newer versions of git.&lt;/em&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.zerosum.org/2010/11/01/pure-git-deploy-workflow.html&quot;&gt;http://blog.zerosum.org/2010/11/01/pure-git-deploy-workflow.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
		&lt;em&gt;while written for specific deployment platforms I ran into the same problems as the ryanfolrence post&lt;/em&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;a href=&quot;http://toroid.org/ams/git-website-howto&quot;&gt;http://toroid.org/ams/git-website-howto&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
		&lt;em&gt;now we&#39;re talking! Not only is this kept up-to-date but works a treat :-)&lt;/em&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you take a peek at the &lt;strong&gt;toroid&lt;/strong&gt; post you&#39;ll read:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;The one-line summary: push into a remote repository that has a detached work tree, and a post-receive hook that runs &amp;quot;git checkout -f&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which I now understand to mean:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;When you push to a remote repo a script will run that updates another directory (that&#39;s the &amp;quot;detached work tree&amp;quot; bit)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perfect! I&#39;ve already got my servers up and running so I don&#39;t want to start moving directories about the place, so for me this is what I did to pretty seamlessly add git deployments&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Create a git repo in &lt;strong&gt;/var/www/html.git/&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have that repo update my working directory &lt;strong&gt;/var/www/html/&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;err... that&#39;s it!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;SSH into the remote machine...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;brush: bash;&quot;&gt;# Move to the /var/www/ folder
cd /var/www/
# Make a new folder for our bare git repo
mkdir html.git
cd html.git
# Intialise a bare git repo
git init --bare
# Create our post-receive hook file (this simply writes 2 lines to the file)
echo -ne &#39;#!/bin/sh\nGIT_WORK_TREE=/var/www/html git checkout -f&#39; &amp;gt; hooks/post-receive
# Make our post-receive file executable
chmod +x hooks/post-receive&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On your local machine you can now push to the remote repository and your working directory will be updated:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;brush: bash;&quot;&gt;# Add the remote repo
git remote add www ssh://username@IPorURL/var/www/html.git
# Now push
git push www master&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And you&#39;re done. That was simple!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quick word of warning&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My local repo also runs on a local server, for me I must be careful of my /uploads/ folder as scripts can write to that directory, I don&#39;t want those files tracked by git so I use a .gitignore file to make sure that no hiccups occur in that department :-)&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>The best programmers CV I could think of</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2012/01/26/the-best-programmers-cv-i-could-think-of.html"/>
		<updated>2012-01-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2012/01/26/the-best-programmers-cv-i-could-think-of</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The curse of the creative type: &lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;my blog needs a new skin&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;my business cards aren&#39;t moo enough&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt; or in my case &lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;my CV is no longer appropriate&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&#39;ve guessed it, I&#39;m looking for full-time employment. Not freelance contracts, more projects or exciting startups (they&#39;re good and all) but I&#39;ve become keen to learn from a the kind of peergroup available in a large company. I think this has grown from conversations with a few peers who have made the transition from freelance / startup to corporation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So without further ado, my CV: (click to view big)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://oodavid.com/cv.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lyf8p4IGmd1qk6dpq.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;My CV on oodavid.com&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The words are my own, but the colour scheme was unashamedly taken from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sublimetext.com/&quot; title=&quot;Sublime Text&quot;&gt;Sublime Text&lt;/a&gt;; I wrote a simple syntax highlighter to make it so :-)&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Mentoring - day 1 - the plan</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2012/01/24/mentoring-day-1-the-plan.html"/>
		<updated>2012-01-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2012/01/24/mentoring-day-1-the-plan</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today was the first proper meeting between myself and Ben &amp;quot;Presentation Player&amp;quot; Cooper, we decided last week that an ideal and productive way to teach / learn JavaScript concepts would be with a real-world project. So we planned:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Presentation-Player/Tweakr/network&quot; title=&quot;Tweakr on GitHub&quot;&gt;Tweakr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;A javascript plugin for tumblr themes&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;that tallies up the tags used by the blogger
		&lt;ul&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;or uses cached data from localstorage (for speed)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;and renders a tag stats graph  
		&lt;ul&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;with logarithmic &amp;quot;levels&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plan has 5 main parts to it (tis on the whiteboard atm):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;polling the tumblr api and collating tag data&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;storing a cache of data (for speed)&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;the stats design and DOM injection&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;creating a simple webpage with instructions on how to install&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;hosting the site on Amazon S3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a quick planning session we went over a few basic javascript concepts: code structure, for loops, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://api.jquery.com/jQuery.each/&quot; title=&quot;$.each&quot;&gt;$.each&lt;/a&gt; helper, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://api.jquery.com/jQuery.getScript/%20&quot; title=&quot;$.getScript&quot;&gt;$.getScript&lt;/a&gt; AJAX shorthand and basic Tumblr API usage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If everything goes to plan, we should be online after about 4 or 5 sessions, keep y&#39;all posted!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>designer tricks - test many fonts on your site</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2012/01/23/designer-tricks-test-many-fonts-on-your-site.html"/>
		<updated>2012-01-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2012/01/23/designer-tricks-test-many-fonts-on-your-site</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When designing font-orientated sites like my very own &lt;a href=&quot;http://oodavid.com/&quot; title=&quot;oodavid! creative problem solver&quot;&gt;oodavid.com&lt;/a&gt; it&#39;s wise to test different fonts to make sure you&#39;ve found just the right match for the job. Using modern techniques it&#39;s pretty straightforward to just include a new font from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/webfonts&quot; title=&quot;Google fonts API&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;google fonts&lt;/a&gt; or another font repository then tweak your CSS to fit the match. Pretty simple stuff really.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what about when you want to test hundreds of different fonts? In those scenarios it&#39;s best to automate those changes so you can just cycle through a ream of fonts to try them out for size. If you are a jQuery user, then you can use something like this in your console:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;brush: js;&quot;&gt;$(&#39;head&#39;).append(&#39;&amp;lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; href=&quot;http://fonts.googleapis.com/css?family=Lobster+Two&amp;amp;v1&amp;amp;v1&quot; /&amp;gt;&#39;);
$(&#39;body&#39;).css(&#39;font-family&#39;, &quot;&#39;Lobster Two&#39;, arial, serif&quot;);&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img alt=&quot;oodavid!&quot; height=&quot;570&quot; src=&quot;http://d3j5vwomefv46c.cloudfront.net/photos/full/333584256.png?Expires=1327323974&amp;amp;Key-Pair-Id=APKAIYVGSUJFNRFZBBTA&amp;amp;Signature=H5NYw4HQOylQ2VtAOPp5CJvXiDJ9EfIEJ~jzrCUGY9a6a~YYvejs8Uq0Igxt2lh0gt08137jz~n~cLGNKUfWHpdsw6ivKt-BY7Jsewqli2fdRp8a~2y7o5wQ9BU58JPtp7DBQoIilmmr0-J3ajQfSUN5GDbo0cYs-7yAtV9NEto_&quot; width=&quot;526&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see this is site specific code but would be easily adapted to fit the needs of your project. In my case I am just using a single font on the body element and allow it to cascade down through the DOM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If google fonts had an API to retrieve a list of all available fonts I would consider writing a jquery plugin or chrome extension to do the dirty work... one for the backburner!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;PS - This blog post was drafted several months ago and has suddenly become relevant; Google Fonts has an API! Once there is a break in my workload I&#39;m going to bash out a Chrome Plugin. As my friend Tim Walker would say... SMASHY BASHY.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/apis/webfonts/docs/developer_api.html#Auth&quot;&gt;http://code.google.com/apis/webfonts/docs/developer_api.html#Auth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.googleapis.com/webfonts/v1/webfonts?key=YOUR-API-KEY&quot;&gt;https://www.googleapis.com/webfonts/v1/webfonts?key=YOUR-API-KEY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;PPS - Turns out &lt;a href=&quot;http://oodavid.tumblr.com/post/7934996106/how-to-test-many-fonts-on-your-site&quot; title=&quot;Whoops&quot;&gt;I&#39;ve already published a post like this&lt;/a&gt;. Oh well :-)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Psuedocode - How to rapidly plan your work</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2012/01/20/psuedocode-how-to-rapidly-plan-your-work.html"/>
		<updated>2012-01-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2012/01/20/psuedocode-how-to-rapidly-plan-your-work</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;At some point in my coding life I got into the habit of writing a sort of comment-soup-pseudocode as a way of planning the work ahead of me. Depending on the language and environment I often end up with a mix of basic programming structures (functions, objects etc) flooded with notes about the work I need to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example I am (right now) writing a sites manager for a client, they need to be able to search for addresses on google, see what sites are nearby on their database and given that information they can then go on to use an existing site, or create a new one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To plan the first part (finding sites) I wrote this psuedo-code:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;brush: javascript;&quot;&gt;NG.sites_manager = {};
NG.sites_manager.show = function(){
	// Check we have google
		// Activate the map
};
NG.sites_manager.geocode_address = function(address, site_id){
	// Geocode the address
		// If we have a site_id
			// NG.sites_manager.add_site(lat, lng, address, site_id, true)
		// Otherwise
			// NG.sites_manager.add_site(lat, lng, address)
};
NG.sites_manager.add_site = function(lat, lng, title, site_id, focal){
	// If it&#39;s focal
		// NG.sites_manager.clear_sites();
	// If we have a site_id
		// If the site exists in the nearby-sites list, exit the function
		// Add the link on the nearby-sites list
	// Add a marker to the map
	// Increment the counter
	// If it&#39;s focal
		// Centre the map
		// Request nearby sites
};
NG.sites_manager.clear_sites = function(){
	// Reset the counter
	// Empty the nearby-sites list
	// Remove the markers
};
NG.sites_manager.get_nearby_sites = function(lat, lng){
	// Request nearby sites
		// For each site
			// NG.sites_manager.add_site(lat, lng, title, site_id)
};&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It serves many useful purposes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;As you write your psuedocode you can visualise the work ahead of you, and the code will already be written in your head by the time you start proper.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Making changes at this stage is trivial.&lt;em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;It is NOT a waste of time, the comments remain in your code.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Something else that I&#39;ve forgotten... err... damn brain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does anyone else work in a similar manner? I&#39;d love to hear some tips and tricks in this area! Now to write my sites-manager...&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>How to write a blog post in a jiffy</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2012/01/18/how-to-write-a-blog-post-in-a-jiffy.html"/>
		<updated>2012-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2012/01/18/how-to-write-a-blog-post-in-a-jiffy</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Write it shoddily, then post it instanty. Theres nothing like fearing your peers think you&#39;re a moron to to speed up the proofing and editing process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lxznbw5w9L1qk6dpq.jpg&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Same as delivering products really.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PS&lt;/strong&gt; - This post was left unedited. Apart from this line. Which is an edit.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Meet my protégé > Ben Cooper</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2012/01/17/meet-my-prot-g-ben-cooper.html"/>
		<updated>2012-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2012/01/17/meet-my-prot-g-ben-cooper</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lxyowcl75O1qk6dpq.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ben Cooper!&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having worked a little with Ben last year, I was pleasantly surprised to receive an email asking if I&#39;d be willing do some tutoring in the ways of javascript; what a major compliment! I&#39;ve just returned from our first meeting at the Settle Down Cafe &lt;em&gt;(notice the pointing dude behind Ben? Legend of a gent, another story)&lt;/em&gt;, it has indeed been settled, we&#39;re to meet every Tuesday in the name of javascript :-) I may have never met a more keen chap than Ben, he&#39;s chomping at the bit and I am very excited to see how the tutoring comes along. Good times my friends, good times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We (very quickly) skimmed over some of the obstacles and have decided to tackle a real-world idea I&#39;ve had sitting in the sketchbook; it&#39;s very javascripty, not overly complex, covers all the basics (DOM manipulation, asyncronous API wetwork etc) and at the end of it there&#39;s going to be something to put our name to. After that? Who knows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More blogposts when it happens :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Addendum&lt;/strong&gt;: What&#39;s a little odd is that when I worked with him I gave him the nickname padawan. Maybe I planted the idea many moons ago and it&#39;s just come to a meaningful fruition? Magic.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>My Chrome Extension > Tweakr</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2012/01/16/my-chrome-extension-tweakr.html"/>
		<updated>2012-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2012/01/16/my-chrome-extension-tweakr</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;No time to blog properly, but I quickly knocked up a chrome plugin that modifies the tumblr interface for extra blogging power!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lxw33hJYEW1qk6dpq.png&quot; alt=&quot;the Tumblr interface with added tags section&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;tweakr add tags to the tumblr interface&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main feature is a new &amp;quot;quicktags&amp;quot; section that helps you maintain a consistency in the way you tag your posts, hurrah!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/hjflbeeefijicpnblegcjmpdnpngjpho?hl=en-US&amp;amp;gl=GB&quot; title=&quot;Tweakr for Chrome&quot;&gt;Tweakr extension&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/oodavid/Tweakr&quot; title=&quot;Tweakr on GitHub&quot;&gt;Tweakr on GitHub&lt;/a&gt; (of course it&#39;s open source you sillies!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More on this later, suggestions welcome!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>CSS / jQuery how to toggle scrollbars for a lightbox</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2012/01/13/css-jquery-how-to-toggle-scrollbars-for-a-lightbox.html"/>
		<updated>2012-01-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2012/01/13/css-jquery-how-to-toggle-scrollbars-for-a-lightbox</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A few months back I was reverse engineering the Facebook photo overlay and noticed that they have employed a very neat trick with-regard-to scrolling; when the photo &amp;quot;popup&amp;quot; is active, the body underneath does not scroll.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s a very subtle UI feature but fixes a thoroughly annoying &amp;quot;bug&amp;quot; for many people. Normally when you view scrollable content in a &amp;quot;lightbox&amp;quot; you would scroll to the bottom of the lightbox and then the PAGE UNDERNEATH STARTS TO SCROLL too, what a buggerlug.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trick is to simply prevent the body from scrolling; using a little CSS we can set the &lt;strong&gt;body&lt;/strong&gt; overflow to be hidden (removes the scrollbars) and put a margin on the &lt;strong&gt;html&lt;/strong&gt; to stop the page moving about (body would expand into the space the scrollbar was otherwise):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;brush: javascript;&quot;&gt;/* Don&#39;t scroll */
html.noscrollbar {margin-right: 15px;}
html.noscrollbar body {overflow: hidden;}&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or if (like me) you&#39;d prefer to leave your CSS be and implement it with jQuery:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;brush: javascript;&quot;&gt;// Remove the scroll
$(&#39;html&#39;).css(&#39;margin-right&#39;, &#39;&#39;);
$(&#39;body&#39;).css(&#39;overflow&#39;, &#39;&#39;);&lt;br/&gt;
// Return the scroll to normal
$(&#39;html&#39;).css(&#39;margin-right&#39;, &#39;15px&#39;);
$(&#39;body&#39;).css(&#39;overflow&#39;, &#39;hidden&#39;);&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use the jQuery method in a hush-hush project that I&#39;ve been working on for the past few months (and for the foreseeable future*) here&#39;s a not-too-revealing screenie&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img alt=&quot;A screenshot&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;http://img11.imageshack.us/img11/2987/scrollbars.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;* a blog post in itself&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Anyone up for a 24-hour hack?</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2012/01/12/anyone-up-for-a-24-hour-hack.html"/>
		<updated>2012-01-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2012/01/12/anyone-up-for-a-24-hour-hack</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;All of life&#39;s best bits happen in brief but intense passages of time:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;birth&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;falling in love&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;earthquakes&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;godzilla attack&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;24 hour nerd a&#39;hack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;iframe width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;435&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/fPTJ3qD1ikk?vq=hd720&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;beautiful, just lovely&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if you&#39;re a nerd, designer, animator in Newcastle (or with a railpass) or just like coffee and pizzas you could do worse than sign up to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.culturecode.co.uk&quot;&gt;The Culture Code Initiative&lt;/a&gt; megahacks and whatnot (a codeworks collaboration).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn&#39;t your average hack either; I believe the primary goal is to seek out and encourage long-term relationships between the arts and digital sectors (think business deals folks). The hope is to bypass those risky stages and get straight to the meat an potatoes of what can be achieved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brilliant people ASSEMBBLLLLLEEEEE!!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Terrible Tumbling</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2012/01/09/terrible-tumbling.html"/>
		<updated>2012-01-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2012/01/09/terrible-tumbling</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;You we&#39;re going to get a post titled &lt;strong&gt;&amp;quot;scope is spaghetti&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt; but instead I&#39;m going to try my best at being angry that my blog was hacked by a tumblr theme (you saw the posts, let&#39;s not be sheepish).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You ready? Here goes...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lxjulkBYAK1qk6dpq.jpg&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Ah well, I might get mad another day!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now, I&#39;m going to use this ill-fitting theme while I have a scour of the internets for something more suitable. Oddly, I found a rather nice premium one t&#39;other day but foolishly I didn&#39;t bookmark it. &lt;em&gt;I ain&#39;t even angry.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suggestions on a postcard...&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Recipe > Mushroom Pâté</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2012/01/08/recipe-mushroom-p-t.html"/>
		<updated>2012-01-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2012/01/08/recipe-mushroom-p-t</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Take a peek at tomorrows menu:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lxgdffkk4U1qk6dpq.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Boeuf Wellington on the (chalboard) menu at home&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tasty or what? So yes, I have been charged with the main course of &lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;Boeuf Wellington&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt; aka steak, pâté and pastry. In the fridge there is some most excellent mushroom and liver pâté chilling for tomorrow. It tastes sublime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;wedge of butter (70g at a guess)&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;3 rashers of bacon,  (probably not necessary)&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;5 shallots, finely chopped (or a regular onion)&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;2 garlic cloves (I actually used paste)&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;300g of mushrooms&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;300g of chicken livers (from the Grainger Market and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/food/techniques/cleaning_chicken_livers&quot; title=&quot;how to clean chicken livers, a video&quot;&gt;cleaned&lt;/a&gt; myself)&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;thyme (err, a bit)&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;splash of port (I imagine martini, sherry etc would be fine too)&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;salt&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;pepper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Melt the butter in a big pan, add the bacon, shallots and garlic, cook for 3-4 min.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add the mushrooms and livers, cook until livers are seared (about 5 min for me)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add the thyme, booze, salt and pepper, cook the booze off. It shouldn&#39;t be totally dry, judge the juice:solids ratio based on your existing pâté experiences (about 10 min)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leave to cool for 15, then food process that bad-boy up! YUM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leave in fridge overnight and devour (I read that the paste does well to be sealed with olive oil, so you probably want to do that too)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Serving suggestion: Apply to beef. Top with pastry.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(I&#39;ll add photos of the pâté tomorrow. When it&#39;s finished)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>node.js - a static file server</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2012/01/04/node-js-a-static-file-server.html"/>
		<updated>2012-01-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2012/01/04/node-js-a-static-file-server</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Previously&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;http://oodavid.tumblr.com/post/15129292268/hello-world-of-node-js&quot; title=&quot;Hello world... of node.js&quot;&gt;Hello world… of node.js&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Serving up a plaintext &amp;quot;Hello world&amp;quot; for every file (see previous) isn&#39;t exactly &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; useful, but it exposed the basic mechanisms we need to make a file server. Today we will update the code to serve &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; file requested, there&#39;s no validation, it&#39;s stupid like that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open up (or create) server.node.js and dump this into it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;brush: javascript;&quot;&gt;/**
 * Static file server
 *   request a file, get a file
 */

// Required libraries
var http	= require(&#39;http&#39;);
var fs		= require(&#39;fs&#39;);

/***************** Simple file server *****************/

// Create the server
var server = http.createServer(function (request, response) {
	// Log the request
	console.log(new Date() + &#39; [&#39; + request.method + &#39;] &#39; + request.url);
	// Serve static files
	if (request.method === &quot;GET&quot;){
		// Manually translate &quot;/&quot; into &quot;/index.html&quot;
		var url = &#39;.&#39; + (request.url == &#39;/&#39; ? &#39;/index.html&#39; : request.url);
		// Read the file and return it
		fs.readFile(url, function(error, content) {
			if (error) {
				// Oh dear.
				console.log(&#39;error loading file &#39; + url + &#39;: &#39;, error);
				// Lets just say missing for now
				response.writeHead(404);
				response.end();
			} else {
				// Lookup the mimetype of the file
				var tmp		= url.lastIndexOf(&quot;.&quot;);
				var ext		= url.substring((tmp + 1));
				var mime	= mimes[ext] || &#39;text/plain&#39;;
				// Write the file
				response.writeHead(200, { &#39;Content-Type&#39;: mime });
				response.end(content, &#39;utf-8&#39;);
			}
		});
	}
});

// Listen on port 1337 and IP 127.0.0.1
server.listen(1337, &quot;127.0.0.1&quot;);
console.log(&#39;Server running at 127.0.0.1:1337&#39;);

/********************* MIME TABLE *********************/

var mimes = {
	&#39;css&#39;:	&#39;text/css&#39;,
	&#39;js&#39;:	&#39;text/javascript&#39;,
	&#39;htm&#39;:	&#39;text/html&#39;,
	&#39;html&#39;:	&#39;text/html&#39;,
	&#39;ico&#39;:	&#39;image/vnd.microsoft.icon&#39;
};&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once again, open up the terminal and run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;brush: bash;&quot;&gt;cd /path/to/folder/
node server.node.js&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE&lt;/strong&gt; - we have changed to the directory of the script file as it would seem that (with my code above) the filesystem library (fs) reads relative to the node process rather than the server file. Which is an interesting learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So now you should create a few new files with your own content:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;/index.html&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;/style.css&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;/script.js&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;/favicon.ico&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then navigate to the server URL, the terminal will output messages like so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;brush: bash;&quot;&gt;Server running at 127.0.0.1:1337
Tue Jan 03 2012 23:54:20 GMT+0000 (GMT) [GET] /
Tue Jan 03 2012 23:54:20 GMT+0000 (GMT) [GET] /script.js
Tue Jan 03 2012 23:54:20 GMT+0000 (GMT) [GET] /style.css
Tue Jan 03 2012 23:54:20 GMT+0000 (GMT) [GET] /favicon.ico&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, index.html references script.js and style.css and my browser has requested favicon.ico on my behalf, they are all served normally. So now we can start making some basic websites with this little server script :-)&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Princess of Milk and Honey</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2012/01/03/princess-of-milk-and-honey.html"/>
		<updated>2012-01-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2012/01/03/princess-of-milk-and-honey</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ll resume the usual code and food and productivity gubbins shortly, but I feel it is my duty to introduce you to the Princess of Milk and Honey&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lx8tn4SiW71qk6dpq.jpg&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Isn&#39;t she lush?&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>New Years Resolutions</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2012/01/02/new-years-resolutions.html"/>
		<updated>2012-01-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2012/01/02/new-years-resolutions</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve had such a lovely time this festive season; lots of food, lovely people and a few odd party-games. I hope you&#39;ve all had a great one too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the stroke of midnight I made 3 resolutions&lt;strong&gt;*&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Bendy&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Handy&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Teeth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bet you&#39;re thinking &lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;what a weirdo, they&#39;re not resolutions&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;, but there&#39;s wisdom in the brevity and I assure you they will serve me well!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of &amp;quot;Bendy&amp;quot; I &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; write &amp;quot;do yoga every week&amp;quot; but what if I don&#39;t like yoga? What if pilates is my poison? If I miss a week will I give up? Lets be honest, it&#39;s a possibility! By simply saying &amp;quot;Bendy&amp;quot; I can have that running in my mind as a little mantra as I go about my business, it&#39;ll seep into the cracks of my year and God help me I &lt;strong&gt;will&lt;/strong&gt; be a bendy man!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What about &amp;quot;Handy&amp;quot; then? Well, right now I &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; fancy going on a journey into woodworking and most likely that&#39;ll be what I end up doing to start with, but as with the &amp;quot;bendy&amp;quot; I&#39;m free to meander into electrics, metalwork etc. etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for &amp;quot;Teeth&amp;quot;... well I haven&#39;t been to the dentists in &lt;strong&gt;over a decade&lt;/strong&gt;, my teeth look fine, but I&#39;m pretty sure I need a filling or two...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That&#39;s all very well David, what about last years? How did they go?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, last year I only made 2 resolutions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Posture &lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Books&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both of which I feel I have made great progress with! Hurrah!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My back and shoulders are looking great, I sometimes catch myself slouching a little but I correct it ASAP. TBH, I didn&#39;t really expect this one to be so enjoyable, it&#39;s really satisfying being the tallest person at the table (even a shortarse like me can tower over a 6ft something with lesser posture). Brilliant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the books, I reckon I&#39;ve averaged about 1-per-week for the year. Including the Harry Potter series, lots of Jasper Fforde, a stack of classics and quite a few business books. While my memory is still shockingly bad, I feel I&#39;ve gained a lot from this one, not-least being that my reading speed is getting better with every book!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a couple of wins under my belt I feel confident that &lt;strong&gt;I will be a well-postured, bendy, well-read handyman with a killer smile&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lx72bufvkW1qk6dpq.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Some Susho&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;strong&gt;edit&lt;/strong&gt;: ths entry looked lonely, here&#39;s some festive sushi I made last week.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;* all the while smooching my lovely Roz under the mistletoe :-)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Hello world... of node.js</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2012/01/01/hello-world-of-node-js.html"/>
		<updated>2012-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2012/01/01/hello-world-of-node-js</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Previously:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://oodavid.tumblr.com/post/15090798307/how-to-install-node-js-on-linux&quot; title=&quot;How to install node.js on Linux&quot;&gt;How to install node.js on Linux&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today we learn how to create a simple webserver with node, it&#39;ll take you about 3 minutes :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create a file called &lt;strong&gt;server.node.js&lt;/strong&gt; and dump this into it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;brush: javascript;&quot;&gt;/**
 * Hello world server
 *   every request to the ip gets the same response
 */

// Require the http library
var http = require(&#39;http&#39;);
// Create the server
var server = http.createServer(function (request, response) {
	// Every request outputs &quot;hello world&quot;
	response.writeHead(200, {&#39;Content-Type&#39;: &#39;text/plain&#39;});
	response.end(&#39;Hello World\n&#39;);
	// And also logs 
	console.log(&#39;Page requested at &#39; + new Date() + &#39;, for &#39; + request.url);
});
// It listens on port 1337 and IP 127.0.0.1
server.listen(1337, &quot;127.0.0.1&quot;);
// For the joy
console.log(&#39;Server running at &lt;a href=&quot;http://127.0.0.1:1337/&#39;&quot;&gt;http://127.0.0.1:1337/&#39;&lt;/a&gt;);&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open up the terminal and run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;brush: bash;&quot;&gt;node server.node.js&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then navigate to the server URL, you can watch the terminal output messages to the following effect:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;brush: bash;&quot;&gt;Server running at &lt;a href=&quot;http://127.0.0.1:1337/&quot;&gt;http://127.0.0.1:1337/&lt;/a&gt;
Page requested at Sun Jan 01 2012 16:23:12 GMT+0000 (GMT) /
Page requested at Sun Jan 01 2012 16:23:12 GMT+0000 (GMT) /favicon.ico&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pretty simple stuff really, and you should be able to quickly see how node.js can become a useful tool to add to your arsenal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Next up:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://oodavid.tumblr.com/post/15290994800/node-js-a-static-file-server&quot; title=&quot;node.js - a static file server&quot;&gt;node.js - a static file server&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>How to install node.js on Linux</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2011/12/31/how-to-install-node-js-on-linux.html"/>
		<updated>2011-12-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2011/12/31/how-to-install-node-js-on-linux</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;How to install node.js on Debian-based Linux distros (Debian, Ubuntu, Mint etc)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 - Install the dependencies (chances are you&#39;ve already got most of these)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;brush: bash;&quot;&gt;sudo apt-get install g++ curl libssl-dev apache2-utils&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 - Then install git (you may already have that too)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;brush: bash;&quot;&gt;sudo apt-get install git-core&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 - Clone the node git repo...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;brush: bash;&quot;&gt;git clone git://github.com/ry/node.git&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4 - Then install&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;brush: bash;&quot;&gt;cd node
./configure
make
sudo make install&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The terminal output will show whether everything went OK, but if you want to be sure&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;brush: bash;&quot;&gt;man node&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Badabing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Next up: &lt;a href=&quot;http://oodavid.tumblr.com/post/15129292268/hello-world-of-node-js&quot; title=&quot;Hello world... of node.js&quot;&gt;Hello world… of node.js&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Right then, time to go to a New-Years-Eve party :-)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Dad's Cart!</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2011/12/28/dads-cart.html"/>
		<updated>2011-12-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2011/12/28/dads-cart</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s been a while since I&#39;ve blogged, but my word have I been a busy boy! I&#39;ve decided to quickly take the opportunity to blog about one of my simpler (ie, quicker to write about) projects; a small jQuery script that adds shopping cart functionality to a website. I wrote it as a small favour for my Dad and is aptly titled &amp;quot;&lt;strong&gt;Dad&#39;s Cart!&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;quot;, we&#39;ve already added it to 2 websites and I&#39;m sure I&#39;ll use it again :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://oodavid.com/dadscart/&quot;&gt;http://oodavid.com/dadscart/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;see it in action here, with instructions&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It works completely on the frontend using localStorage to store the users cart, all the developer needs to do is tweak their markup a little and you&#39;re off. What it doesn&#39;t do is validate the data, nor connect to an e-payment system, that&#39;s your call. &lt;em&gt;For us, we had 1 site connect to Barclays PDQ and another to PayPal, so we left the payment part out :-)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lwx4nmJX781qk6dpq.png&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;you have 4 items in your cart ;-)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lwozfsozJu1qk6dpq.jpg&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Dad sunning it up :-)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Social Media Revolution</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2011/11/17/social-media-revolution.html"/>
		<updated>2011-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2011/11/17/social-media-revolution</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Another great video by Socialnomics&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;iframe width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;435&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/3SuNx0UrnEo?vq=hd720&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;pretty thought provoking stuff&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>CultureHackNorth - poke that!</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2011/11/13/culturehacknorth-poke-that.html"/>
		<updated>2011-11-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2011/11/13/culturehacknorth-poke-that</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So I&#39;m at the arse-end of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://culturehacknorth.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Culture Hack North&lt;/a&gt; in Leeds; I&#39;ve been awake for about 30 hours and I thought it&#39;d be nice to write a blog and introduce my project and walk through the process...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://khakaure.oodavid.com/&quot;&gt;Khakaure!!!&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt; get yer click on&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lulhxwDF1u1qk6dpq.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pencil sketch of the interface&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;after settling on an idea, I drafted the original plan. Like a fool I made it in portrait...&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lulhyvG8hC1qk6dpq.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Revised sketch&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;new plan in a more webby sensible layout&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point I wrote myself some tasklists, things like &amp;quot;mockup interface layout&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;setup webserver&amp;quot; etc after all the obvious bits and bobs I was in unknown territory; how to do those mad graph &lt;em&gt;thingies&lt;/em&gt;... You know, the wibbly wobbly ones...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lulhzwDndx1qk6dpq.png&quot; alt=&quot;First bit of coding, a greyscale graph&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;well, the first step was to see about drawing lines and circles, I did that with &lt;a href=&quot;http://raphaeljs.com/&quot;&gt;raphael.js&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since my memory is terrible it took me about an hour to remember the name of themodels I was thinking of; FORCE-DIRECTED GRAPHS innit! Well, some googling and wikipedia research showed me that you can make a rather decent FDG by:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Modelling your connections as SPRINGS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;the circles want to be a certain distance apart&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Making all the circles repel each other a bit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;so they bustle for space and spread out sensibly&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;or if you prefer, Hooke&#39;s Law and Coulomb&#39;s Law. Bosh&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_luli2svE4f1qk6dpq.png&quot; alt=&quot;After applying force-directed code to the graph it looks like a parachute&quot;/&gt;
	Hooke&#39;s law models the springs and Coolomb&#39;s law models the distribution
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making the force-directed graph took a reasonable amount of testing as when you have 6 variables that all change the way the system feels it quickly baffles you, which is why I mocked up a little settings panel to quickly try lots of different values of each&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lulifuXaRn1qk6dpq.png&quot; alt=&quot;Ability to tweak the internal settings like spring strength, length and forces&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;this thing is so bloody fun to use I left it in as a feature!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All that was left now was the side-pane that adapts to the data inside each node of the graph; that was pretty strightforward, it can detect:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;titles&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;descriptions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;images&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;maps (google baby!)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;everything else gets output in a table-like way so you can make your own mind up about what it means. The database, while designed and functional is sadly devoid of data in a structure that plays well with the system; we&#39;re looking at that &lt;em&gt;right now&lt;/em&gt; and I hope to improve it at some point soon. Suffice to say I&#39;ve thoroughly enjoyed the hack; this &amp;quot;nodegarden&amp;quot; is an idea I&#39;ve been toying with for just too long and this was the perfect opportunity to have a go!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, where&#39;s my bed...? Oh yeah, 6 hours away...&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>CSS a tip for printing :-)</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2011/11/04/css-a-tip-for-printing.html"/>
		<updated>2011-11-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2011/11/04/css-a-tip-for-printing</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Super quick tip today, if you want to style your pages for printing then you really &lt;strong&gt;must&lt;/strong&gt; add this to your arsenal of snippets:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;brush: css;&quot;&gt;.selector {
	page-break-inside: avoid;
	page-break-after: auto;
}&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;which stops elements from being sliced in half when they get printed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lu4truslXN1qk6dpq.png&quot; alt=&quot;Shows a block element split over two printed pages&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lu4ts0965d1qk6dpq.png&quot; alt=&quot;Shows the same element but the whole thing has dropped onto the second page&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;before and after&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>GF Buckwheat parcels, they're flippin' awesome! (recipe)</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2011/11/03/gf-buckwheat-parcels-theyre-flippin-awesome.html"/>
		<updated>2011-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2011/11/03/gf-buckwheat-parcels-theyre-flippin-awesome</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m excited with this mornings breakfast photos so the recipe will have to wait till the end...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lu2t7qUeFh1qk6dpq.jpg&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Fry up a buckwheat crêpe till the edges start to curl&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lu2tl4Yyoq1qk6dpq.jpg&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;...once curly, flip the pancake and crack an egg onto the cooked side&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lu2t4wTEAm1qk6dpq.jpg&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;...add cooked bacon and mushrooms, cherry toms, spinach, cheese, salt &amp;amp; pepper&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lu2t3aRdPz1qk6dpq.jpg&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;...fold in the edges to make a parcel, this can be a bit fiddly - I have faith in you&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lu2xm1qX181qk6dpq.jpg&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;...flip it to make sure the egg is cooked through (I don&#39;t mind it runny tbh, but hey!)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CONSUME! DIGEST! ENJOY!&lt;/strong&gt; You are now eating my favourite breakfast evar. It&#39;s just the job; one pancake usually does for breakfast (lunch, tea etc) unless you&#39;re a greedy bugger like me in which case you&#39;ll need two to make you groan and moan. WITH JOY.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recipe for the Buckwheat batter (to make about 6-8 pancakes):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;mix up this lot&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
		&lt;ul&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;80g of buckwheat flour&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;80g of chestnut (or regular wheat) flour&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;pinch o&#39; salt&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;2 beaten eggs&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;then gradually stir in&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
		&lt;ul&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;160ml milk&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;240ml water&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;and finally add&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
		&lt;ul&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;a wee splash of olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use it straight away if you like, but it&#39;s at it&#39;s best after resting in the fridge for a couple of hours. BLAMMO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Next time I might find the lowest denominator for the measures; tis always easier to multiply UP than divide DOWN. Hmm...&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Weekend app - the votes are in!</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2011/11/01/weekend-app-the-votes-are-in.html"/>
		<updated>2011-11-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2011/11/01/weekend-app-the-votes-are-in</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well that was exciting! For a moment Nelson de Craab was in the lead only to be pipped by OOSubs after a dinner party and some in-person votes were cast - crazy times. &lt;em&gt;They could have Tweeted me from the other end of the room... some people eh?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://chart.apis.google.com/chart?chs=500x580&amp;amp;cht=pc&amp;amp;chco=3072F3%7C6F9BF3%7CA9C2F3,FF9900%7CFFB74A%7CFFD493&amp;amp;chd=s:ECD,FEB&amp;amp;chdl=via+Twitter%7Cvia+Blog%7CIn+person%7COOSubs+-+8+votes%7CNelson+de+Craab+-+6+votes%7CDigital+Whiteboard+-+2+votes&amp;amp;chdlp=b%7C3,4,5,0,1,2&amp;amp;chdls=676767,13&amp;amp;chp=2.91&amp;amp;chma=%7C65,15&amp;amp;chtt=Weekend+app+-+OOSubs+wins!&amp;amp;chts=676767,24&quot; alt=&quot;The vote is in! OOSubs wins :-)&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;580&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So on the 12&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; and 13&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; of November I shall be doing a power session &lt;em&gt;(possibly at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://culturehacknorth.co.uk/2011/09/culture-hack-north-leeds-2011/&quot;&gt;Leeds Culture Hack&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/em&gt; working on the OOSubs project! I&#39;ll not be going in blind though - at some point between now and then I&#39;ll sketch up a set of wireframes that I reckon is doable in the timescale, I&#39;ll keep you all posted :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Serious thanks to everyone that voted; what better than a vote when you&#39;re feeling indecisive?! Brill.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>How to write a perfect daily task list</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2011/10/28/how-to-write-a-perfect-daily-task-list.html"/>
		<updated>2011-10-28T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2011/10/28/how-to-write-a-perfect-daily-task-list</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&#39;ll announce the winner of the &amp;quot;weekend project&amp;quot; poll in the next post ;-)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are the rules that I give myself when drafting my daily task list. Your task list MUST...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;be the first thing you do every day&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;I write mine after breakfast before brushing my teeth / showering etc&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;use yesterdays list as a startpoint&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;in case there&#39;s anything incompleted or left-over&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fit on a small piece of paper&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;I usually go for a piece of A4 folded twice, gives you 8 days of lists :-)&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;have estimated times for each task&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;this helps you stay on track as you work&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;have a bonus item at the end that you want to do&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;only tackle this if you complete your list, gives you something to look forward to!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So for example, today I have:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_ltrtfl2jgz1qk6dpq.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A short, hand-written list with allocated times for each action&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;intentions&amp;quot; is a little idea I&#39;m throwing about, if I create the wireframes I can happily file it away in my ideas box knowing that the soul of it is not lost should I wish to pursue it another day&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the rules cobbled together from a book called &lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;The Decision Book: Fifty Models for Strategic Thinking&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt; which I read in the bath a few months ago - for serious workers I now consider it an essential read! GET ON IT FOLKS&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Vote for a weekend app!</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2011/10/27/vote-for-a-weekend-app.html"/>
		<updated>2011-10-27T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2011/10/27/vote-for-a-weekend-app</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s been decided that on the weekend of the 12&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; of Nov I shall &amp;quot;scratch the itch&amp;quot; and create something using my nerdy skills - after skimming my &lt;strong&gt;Ideas Bucket&lt;/strong&gt; (a big, daft google doc full of ideas) I have rounded up a few non-too consuming ideas; write me a comment, tweet, wall-post, carrier pigeon etc and let me know what you think I should do!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1 - Revisit oosubs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;subs.oodavid.com has only ever been functional for me and Roz (I have to update it manually), over the weekend I will create a backend so that anyone can upload subtitles for films they are going to see; thus the hard-of-hearing community can enjoy the benefit of seeing films &lt;em&gt;anytime&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2 - Write a kids book for a friend &amp;quot;Nelson de craab&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Years ago I came across a story that my good friend Laurie wrote when she was just a sprogg; I promised myself that I would write it up should she ever get preggers. Lets just say she has a BUMP! The story was about a crab who lost his shell and was trying to find it by asking his sea-beastie mates, my memory is missing an ending so I&#39;ll have to figure that one out...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3 - Create a digital whiteboard&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have the whiteboard, and I can pimp it to be interactive using hacked together wii parts and open-source software. Why? For awesome presentations of course :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;GET YER VOTE ON FOOLS!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Now *that's* a whiteboard!</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2011/10/19/now-thats-a-whiteboard.html"/>
		<updated>2011-10-19T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2011/10/19/now-thats-a-whiteboard</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So you saw the raw projector mount I rigged up on Saturday right? Well I spent some time on Sunday painting the &amp;quot;screen&amp;quot; with whiteboard paint; now I have a home cinema &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; somewhere to brainstorm my ideas - huzzah!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;[I was going to upload a picture of a white wall, but I&#39;m confident you can imagine a large white square in a sea of magnolia... you&#39;re an intelligent bunch]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lt7p4lMLiX1qk6dpq.jpg&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;re-painted, pimpin&#39; projector mount&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_ltbc8oRlYa1qk6dpq.jpg&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;...which is also painted with voodoo-paint - wheeee!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lt7qlp1n1l1qk6dpq.jpg&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;the projected image looks considerably sharper for the white surface (&amp;#8216;twas magnolia), plus if you lie on the floor you can pretend you&#39;re at the cinema :-)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_ltbc9gMKzl1qk6dpq.jpg&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;finally, you can deface the &amp;quot;bad-guys&amp;quot; (I like Snape really)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used 2 tins of &lt;a title=&quot;Promain Paint&quot; href=&quot;http://www.promain.co.uk/product/Rustoleum_Dry_Erase_Paint_whiteboard_id4091&quot;&gt;Rust-Oleum Dry-Erase Paint&lt;/a&gt; bought via Promain (next-day-delivery) and cost me ~£45, when you consider the cost of a new whiteboard-screen it works out rather cheap. If I was painting a larger area I would probably try ideapaint.com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I&#39;ll be rigging up &lt;a title=&quot;Johnny Lee!&quot; href=&quot;http://johnnylee.net/projects/wii/&quot;&gt;interactivity with a Wiimote&lt;/a&gt; when I can slot in the time, that&#39;ll be fun :-)&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Today I made... a projector ceiling mount!</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2011/10/15/today-i-made-a-projector-ceiling-mount.html"/>
		<updated>2011-10-15T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2011/10/15/today-i-made-a-projector-ceiling-mount</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Try and buy a &amp;quot;non poop&amp;quot; ceiling mount for a projector and you&#39;ll be lucky to get one for under £40, so I did the logical thing and made one for about £2.50 - and it&#39;s perfect for my needs! Hurray for wood :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lt4chxKbcG1qk6dpq.jpg&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;the low-rez photo hides all manner of sins&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To finish the job I am applying Rust-Oleum Dry-Erase paint onto the surface opposite to act as a dual purpose mega-whiteboard and projector screen. Tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>on working with your Dad :-)</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2011/10/11/on-working-with-your-dad.html"/>
		<updated>2011-10-11T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2011/10/11/on-working-with-your-dad</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;At the tender age of 13, as my friends were picking up paper-rounds I found myself picking up tomes of programming books - for the fun. My favourite hobby was trying to grasp something firmly outside of the normal school experience, programming and physics were the most exciting - there&#39;s just so many boggling ideas to transcend!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going back it makes a lot of sense; my Dad had recently moved from his shared office space in Washington to the spare room at home, as a result a plethora of books made their way back with him; technical guides, exploded isometrics, specsheets, pantone swatches, machine manuals, programming guides, interface conventions and buggerload of the other reference material that he collected over the years. Given my appetite for the extra-curricular I consumed many of these books with a passion - I put them into action when I &amp;quot;interned&amp;quot; for my Dad drawing technical illustrations in Flash 3 (anyone remember that?) for a kids game. Happy times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Little did I know that it would be the start of a long and enjoyable working relationship; in the past 14 years 10 have been with Pappy King! How lovely is that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been working with him for the past 3 months on a few large projects and I&#39;m enjoying it more than ever! Our combined experience is so complimentary that it was a literal &amp;quot;head nod&amp;quot; and on to business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lsw7d2bLHp1qk6dpq.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Chris &#39;Kingster&#39; King&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;3 cheers for Pappy King! He really is a jolly good fellow!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Unripe chillis? 'ave a banana!</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2011/10/04/unripe-chillis-ave-a-banana.html"/>
		<updated>2011-10-04T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2011/10/04/unripe-chillis-ave-a-banana</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A little factoid:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Fruits pump out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ethylene&quot;&gt;Ethylene&lt;/a&gt; hormone when ripening&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ethylene&quot;&gt;Ethylene&lt;/a&gt; stimulates the ripening of fruit&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li style=&quot;font-size: 80%;&quot;&gt;Fruits pump out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ethylene&quot;&gt;Ethylene&lt;/a&gt; hormone when ripening&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li style=&quot;font-size: 80%;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ethylene&quot;&gt;Ethylene&lt;/a&gt; stimulates the ripening of fruit&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li style=&quot;font-size: 50%;&quot;&gt;Fruits pump out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ethylene&quot;&gt;Ethylene&lt;/a&gt; hormone when ripening&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li style=&quot;font-size: 50%;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ethylene&quot;&gt;Ethylene&lt;/a&gt; stimulates the ripening of fruit&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;...and so on!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Armed with this knowledge I decided to turn to the humble banana, a well known purveyor of quality Ethylene to help with the ripening of my left-over Scotch Bonnets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lsj7psyOBe1qk6dpq.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;some Scotch Bonnets sitting on a banana&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;...these fellas were all green 2 days ago! Good work humble bananas :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally I find that a green chilli is much like eating spicy grass, a little bitter and chloroformish - whereas a brightly coloured chilli has so much more depth of flavour; akin to being kicked in the face by a fruit. This is what we should all strive for in our chillis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nota Bene&lt;/strong&gt; - I have decided on my next &amp;quot;ideas&amp;quot; post, shall be making it soon, it&#39;s a goodun!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Ignite Newcastle, subtitle love and sushi</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2011/09/30/ignite-newcastle-subtitle-love-and-sushi.html"/>
		<updated>2011-09-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2011/09/30/ignite-newcastle-subtitle-love-and-sushi</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I love Thursdays, I love all days really; there&#39;s always something happening to make you smile! Yesterday was no exception, after a good day&#39;s graft &lt;em&gt;(I must blog about this contract soon)&lt;/em&gt; I popped over to the Codeworks &lt;a title=&quot;Ignite site&quot; href=&quot;http://ignite.oreilly.com/&quot;&gt;Ignite&lt;/a&gt; event to have my neurons tickled and tickled they were!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first speaker &lt;a title=&quot;Love your larder&quot; href=&quot;http://www.loveyourlarder.com/&quot;&gt;Tristan Watson&lt;/a&gt; (a beautiful soul) talked about how an idea is only important once it&#39;s been acted on and to my mega joy he used one of my sideprojects as an example!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lsbxmnUxga1qk6dpq.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;mobile subtitles showing back to the future!&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;he was so kind about it I did a little blush!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then watched Dan Gilmore talk about immersive technologies, a new face to me but so passionate! Love it! He sparked the memory of a thought I had as a child; &lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;what would swapping sensory inputs feel like?&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt; - if there&#39;s another Ignite event I may ask to talk about this cause it&#39;s such a giggle of a thought experiment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Let the truncation begin - I should be working!!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;We heard about finances from Jonathan Gold&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;I noted that I need to talk to him about a concept business plan with a super-short-term exit strategy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Peter Hirst talked about hidden gems and easter eggs in technology&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sparked another weekend tinkering of an idea, maybe next month ;-)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Dan Kolodziej (pronounced ko-lod-gee) went on a MEGA-TANGENT starting with shoes, onto Wi-Fi, cruised through Africa, financial institutions, and back to shoes again. DAN&#39;S SHOES that is.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reminded me of frontline SMS - must see how that&#39;s evolving soon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;David Erasmus (what a name!!) showed us some heart-warming holiday snaps then asked us about the nature of openness and friendship and why things happen the way they do&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I wrote - must buy a school bus&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had to cut the event short cause to cycle home and make SUSHI!!!! Yes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lsbyebeuFr1qk6dpq.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Eating Sushi!&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&#39;t get a shot of everyone; there was no incentive to move &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;away&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; from the food. That&#39;s just dumb. That last sushi was named &lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;the loneliest maki&amp;quot;, &lt;/em&gt;we proceeded to make it some &amp;quot;friends&amp;quot; then eat them too. We all had to lie down and ride it out cause we made soooo much!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&#39;t forget kids, every night is food night&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Self portrait...</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2011/09/26/self-portrait.html"/>
		<updated>2011-09-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2011/09/26/self-portrait</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Turns out I am not much more than a squiggle...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_ls4txtG7Id1qk6dpq.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;You can draw my face with just 4 lines!&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Might use something like this for my business card - I don&#39;t have one yet y&#39;see. Needs text though, how abooouuut:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;oodavid! what a nice business card you have...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;aka &amp;quot;the classic&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;David King - create problem solver - full service web development&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;aka &amp;quot;what it says on my website&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;David King - STRAIGHT UP NERD&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;aka &amp;quot;the reality&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;David King - who ate all the &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;π&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;aka &amp;quot;welcome to my brain&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...who am I kidding, words aren&#39;t really my strong-point, I&#39;ll probably just go with a subtle off-white colour. a tasteful thickness and a watermark.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Seminar of sales-ness</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2011/09/23/seminar-of-sales-ness.html"/>
		<updated>2011-09-23T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2011/09/23/seminar-of-sales-ness</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fun fact: when I was 17 I learned from my brother that you can just walk into random lectures at University and people probably wont notice, I did that for a few months and it was awesome. If you&#39;re lucky it will be a good lecture :-)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So anyhow, yesterday was rather epic - &lt;a title=&quot;Durham Lane&quot; href=&quot;http://www.durhamlane.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Richard Lane&lt;/a&gt;, sales-dude extraordinaire, got my little neurons fired up about how we communicate and think about sales and after-sales processes and logic. Frankly a lot more than I can cover here (I have work to do) suffice to say it was very insightful, go see the man if you can! Why? This is why:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lryupolgB91qk6dpq.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Some pencil notes from the seminar&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;My journal writings are often a bit odd, mind I can &lt;strong&gt;usually&lt;/strong&gt; translate them correctly...&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;Richard&#39;s language and presentation style is incredible, he has just made an example sales pitch for &lt;em&gt;NOTHING&lt;/em&gt; and I want to buy it. Whatever it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brilliant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the things he presented was a concept for sales Qualification called The Magic 35 Qualification Toolkit™, which reminded me of my Leads Profile Radar Diagrams (earlier blog post). So last night with an hour free I decided to knock up a &amp;quot;radar maker&amp;quot; that we can use to generate Lead Profiling diagrams and Magic 35 diagrams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://oodavid.com/radarmaker/&quot;&gt;http://oodavid.com/radarmaker/&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt; wooo!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately I hope to add more presets for other stages of the sales process to make up:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Lead Profiling&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Qualification&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Requirement&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Evidence&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Acquisition&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Closing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hurray for brainwaves!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>The year in food</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2011/09/20/the-year-in-food.html"/>
		<updated>2011-09-20T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2011/09/20/the-year-in-food</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In roughly chronological order, the most bestest food that I photographed in the past 12 months... Advanced apologies for ensuing hunger :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lrrzv9qjRa1qk6dpq.jpg&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;a mega pizza, with everything as a topping&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lrrzvtVr1u1qk6dpq.jpg&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;breakfast in bed with a smile, I love you woman!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lrrzwvATYM1qk6dpq.jpg&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;coast to coast midway treat, consumed with the appetite of a wolf&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lrrzygymcY1qk6dpq.jpg&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;a Halloween hotpot, no &amp;quot;after&amp;quot; shot cause it got eaten too quickly!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lrrzz3PJJd1qk6dpq.jpg&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;pumpkin soup - this was EPIC, we&#39;ll be redoing this as soon as I see a pumpkin in the market&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lrrzzuTzCg1qk6dpq.jpg&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt; pineapple burger to fit the aussy film &amp;quot;Priscilla Queen of the Desert&amp;quot;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lrs01iR8dA1qk6dpq.jpg&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;a tarragon / strogonoff hybrid or &amp;quot;tarragonoff&amp;quot; if you will&lt;br&gt;
		I made this up as I went and have since lost the recipe :-(&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lrs02bDfZf1qk6dpq.jpg&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;waffles, lots of waffles. with bacon. and coffee. every other weekend&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lrs0417uIK1qk6dpq.jpg&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;the finest soup in the world (I&#39;m making that tonight actually, might post a recipe 2moz)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lrs05aMxLn1qk6dpq.jpg&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;litres of stock! we don&#39;t waste round these parts!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lrs063wiVb1qk6dpq.jpg&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;kippers with grilled tomatoes, my god are this good&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lrs070VRZY1qk6dpq.jpg&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;and finally a truckload of sushi, thank you Roz for the introduction, I will always treasure the sushi&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photographing food is a bit of an art, the good stuff gets a pic but the great stuff is so mesmorizing you forget to take a snap! There&#39;s a few notable missing dishes here; all the desserts, roasts, marinaded meats, ducks, curries... I could go on...&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>A journey into literature</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2011/09/19/a-journey-into-literature.html"/>
		<updated>2011-09-19T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2011/09/19/a-journey-into-literature</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;With the recent passing of the inspirational and &amp;quot;unreasonable&amp;quot; &lt;a title=&quot;Michael S. Hart&quot; href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Michael_S._Hart&quot;&gt;Michael S. Hart&lt;/a&gt;, founder of &lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Project Gutenberd&quot; href=&quot;http://www.gutenberg.org/&quot;&gt;Project Gutenberg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt; I thought that it would be good to share my sapling journey into literature.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve had a recurring conversation with my programming peers that once you&#39;ve finished your day of coding &lt;em&gt;(aka, reading and writing)&lt;/em&gt; the idea of staring at a book for a few hours sounds too much like work. In the new year I made myself a promise; to start my journey reading &amp;quot;important&amp;quot; books; sure, knowing the latest trends in HTML5 is handy but being able to chat away with my friends and strangers about more popular books and topics is just epic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the recommendations of Roz and her family I started reading Jasper Fforde; he may be the &lt;strong&gt;perfect&lt;/strong&gt; writer with which to start a journey into literature; he&#39;s funny, intelligent, silly and the focus of his books is literature itself - I promptly read the entire &amp;quot;Thursday Next&amp;quot; series:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The Eyre Affair - Jasper Fforde&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Lost in a Good Book - Jasper Fforde&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The Well of Lost Plots - Jasper Fforde&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Something Rotten - Jasper Fforde&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;First Among Sequels - Jasper Fforde&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Epic. After that I promised to give Jane Eyre and Pride and Prejudice a read, I now understand why Jasper Fforde writes them central to his novels - because they&#39;re excellent! The stories are well known so I&#39;ll skip those and just note that the writing styles of both are just beautiful, I really like the idea that a writer can skip over &amp;quot;obvious&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;banal&amp;quot; segments and just focus on the important bits - took that one onboard :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Pride and Prejudice - Jane Austin&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Jane Eyre - Charlotte Brontë&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up was a bit of a read of necessity, those that know me personally will understand why I felt it was important to read about The Eden Project in Cornwall (lets just say that I visited recently with a &amp;quot;side project&amp;quot; in my pocket). This book was really insightful; I was hoping for a romantic story of flora and fauna but while that served as the preface and backdrop the majority of the book was about the unlikely people that made the project a reality - it&#39;s quite astounding that The Eden Project exists. My hats off to them all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Eden - Tim Smit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My most recent read is Slaughterhouse-Five, a short and fragmented anti-war book written about (in a roundabout way) the Dresden Bombing in WWII. The one thing that I will take away from this book is the idea that all the moments in our lives will always exist, it&#39;s simply our experience of time that makes us think otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Slaughterhouse-Five, or The Children&#39;s Crusade: A Duty-Dance with Death - Kurt Vonnegut&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that brings us up to the now, I have quite a list of books I want to read but next up is one I read as a teenager on the recommendation of one of my favourite teachers, Mr Hunter (Physics). It&#39;s about how we perceive dimensions and reality; I think it will be the right bedmate to Slaughterhouse-Five with it&#39;s warped sense of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Flatland: A Romance of Many Dimensions - Edwin A. Abbott&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lrrg88f0gK1qk6dpq.gif&quot; alt=&quot;FlatLand - a romance of many dimensions&quot; style=&quot;background-color: #FFFFFF;&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Remember folks, if you&#39;re ever in Cody, Wyoming, ask for Wild Bob.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Idea - The Music of a Time and Place</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2011/09/15/idea-the-music-of-a-time-and-place.html"/>
		<updated>2011-09-15T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2011/09/15/idea-the-music-of-a-time-and-place</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;An idea for a streaming music service (or maybe a mashup powered by their APIs); select a location and a time and be exposed to the &amp;quot;experience&amp;quot; of that era. Lovely&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://player.vimeo.com/video/28994636?title=0&amp;amp;byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&quot; width=&quot;522&quot; height=&quot;300&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Idea - The Music of a Time and Place&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Idea - Social Intentions on Google Plus</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2011/09/14/idea-social-intentions-on-google-plus.html"/>
		<updated>2011-09-14T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2011/09/14/idea-social-intentions-on-google-plus</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;An idea to evolve the way events work on social platforms like Google Plus / Facebook; to create a step before the event called an intention. These intentions give users a place to discuss the idea, to set a date etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The intentions could also act as a sort of &amp;quot;to do&amp;quot; list with people - it would be lovely to visit someone&#39;s page and be reminded of the things that you agreed to do someday and be able to discuss them and make them a reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://player.vimeo.com/video/29034180?title=0&amp;amp;byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&quot; width=&quot;522&quot; height=&quot;300&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Idea - Social Intentions on Google Plus&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Profiling your leads... WITH RADAR DIAGRAMS</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2011/09/13/profiling-your-leads-with-radar-diagrams.html"/>
		<updated>2011-09-13T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2011/09/13/profiling-your-leads-with-radar-diagrams</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last month I was doodling radar diagrams of people&#39;s characteristics and trying to match them to personality types (interesting but maybe a bit odd), but regardless it led me to do the same for different &lt;em&gt;types&lt;/em&gt; of freelance work. After a little &lt;a title=&quot;Google Charts API&quot; href=&quot;http://code.google.com/apis/chart/&quot;&gt;Google Charts&lt;/a&gt; tinkering I now have a few for your viewing pleasure - they compare&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Safe Returns - are you gonna get paid?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;High Returns - are you getting paid a lot?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Quick Returns - aka good payment terms&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Low Input - amount of &amp;quot;hands-on&amp;quot; needed&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Further Work - odds of a referral / follow up lead&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Likelyhood - odds of getting the work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img height=&quot;400&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; alt=&quot;Disaster Recovery &amp;amp; Emergency Work&quot; src=&quot;https://chart.googleapis.com/chart?cht=r&amp;amp;chs=400x400&amp;amp;chtt=Disaster+Recovery+%2F+Emergency+Work&amp;amp;chxl=1:%7CSafe+Returns%7CHigh+Returns%7CQuick+Returns%7CLow+Input%7CFurther+Work%7CLikelyhood&amp;amp;chd=t:80,80,80,70,50,30,80&amp;amp;chxt=y,x&amp;amp;chls=2&amp;amp;chco=CC3366&amp;amp;chts=000000,18&amp;amp;chxr=0,0.0,100.0&amp;amp;chxp=0,0,20,40,60,80,100&amp;amp;chxs=0,000000,12%7C1,000000,12&amp;amp;chm=o,CC3366,0,-1,8&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img height=&quot;400&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; alt=&quot;Consultancy&quot; src=&quot;https://chart.googleapis.com/chart?cht=r&amp;amp;chs=400x400&amp;amp;chtt=Consultancy&amp;amp;chxl=1:%7CSafe+Returns%7CHigh+Returns%7CQuick+Returns%7CLow+Input%7CFurther+Work%7CLikelyhood&amp;amp;chd=t:60,70,80,90,50,50,60&amp;amp;chxt=y,x&amp;amp;chls=2&amp;amp;chco=CC3366&amp;amp;chts=000000,18&amp;amp;chxr=0,0.0,100.0&amp;amp;chxp=0,0,20,40,60,80,100&amp;amp;chxs=0,000000,12%7C1,000000,12&amp;amp;chm=o,CC3366,0,-1,8&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img height=&quot;400&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; alt=&quot;Public Sector&quot; src=&quot;https://chart.googleapis.com/chart?cht=r&amp;amp;chs=400x400&amp;amp;chtt=Public+Sector&amp;amp;chxl=1:%7CSafe+Returns%7CHigh+Returns%7CQuick+Returns%7CLow+Input%7CFurther+Work%7CLikelyhood&amp;amp;chd=t:90,70,25,60,40,40,90&amp;amp;chxt=y,x&amp;amp;chls=2&amp;amp;chco=CC3366&amp;amp;chts=000000,18&amp;amp;chxr=0,0.0,100.0&amp;amp;chxp=0,0,20,40,60,80,100&amp;amp;chxs=0,000000,12%7C1,000000,12&amp;amp;chm=o,CC3366,0,-1,8&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img height=&quot;400&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; alt=&quot;Startup&quot; src=&quot;https://chart.googleapis.com/chart?cht=r&amp;amp;chs=400x400&amp;amp;chtt=Startup&amp;amp;chxl=1:%7CSafe+Returns%7CHigh+Returns%7CQuick+Returns%7CLow+Input%7CFurther+Work%7CLikelyhood&amp;amp;chd=t:15,60,20,20,70,80,15&amp;amp;chxt=y,x&amp;amp;chls=2&amp;amp;chco=CC3366&amp;amp;chts=000000,18&amp;amp;chxr=0,0.0,100.0&amp;amp;chxp=0,0,20,40,60,80,100&amp;amp;chxs=0,000000,12%7C1,000000,12&amp;amp;chm=o,CC3366,0,-1,8&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://chart.googleapis.com/chart?cht=r&amp;amp;chs=400x400&amp;amp;chtt=In+Another+Reality&amp;amp;chxl=1:%7CSafe+Returns%7CHigh+Returns%7CQuick+Returns%7CLow+Input%7CFurther+Work%7CLikelyhood&amp;amp;chd=t:100,100,100,100,100,100,100&amp;amp;chxt=y,x&amp;amp;chls=2&amp;amp;chco=CC3366&amp;amp;chts=000000,18&amp;amp;chxr=0,0.0,100.0&amp;amp;chxp=0,0,20,40,60,80,100&amp;amp;chxs=0,000000,12%7C1,000000,12&amp;amp;chm=o,CC3366,0,-1,8&quot; alt=&quot;In Another Reality&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;400&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course this applies to my own experiences of freelance and charts the criteria I deem important, hopefully you can see how data like this can help make decisions. In my case drive me to say no to certain types of work and hunt down others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get in the comments and with some feedback I&#39;ll look at making a printable cheat-sheet for your wall :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you want to create your own, and to save you reading (the rather excellent) documentation, this is the URL format I used to create these.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;https://chart.googleapis.com/chart?cht=r
	&amp;amp;chs=400x400
	&amp;amp;chtt=Consultancy
	&amp;amp;chxl=1:|Safe+Returns|High+Returns|Quick+Returns|Low+Input|Further+Work|Likelyhood
	&amp;amp;chd=t:60,70,80,90,50,50,60
	&amp;amp;chxt=y,x
	&amp;amp;chls=2
	&amp;amp;chco=CC3366
	&amp;amp;chts=000000,18
	&amp;amp;chxr=0,0.0,100.0
	&amp;amp;chxp=0,0,20,40,60,80,100
	&amp;amp;chxs=0,000000,12|1,000000,12
	&amp;amp;chm=o,CC3366,0,-1,8&lt;/pre&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>jQuery plugin - favicon notifier</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2011/09/12/jquery-plugin-favicon-notifier.html"/>
		<updated>2011-09-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2011/09/12/jquery-plugin-favicon-notifier</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve written a few jQuery plugins but most of them have been super specific to my needs; decided to tidy up one of last weeks tinkerings and publish it to the old &amp;#8216;hub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The jQuery Favicon Notifier&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Push numerical notifiers to the favicon in your browser, change the font, position and icon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;jQuery Favicon Notifier on oodavid.com&quot; href=&quot;http://oodavid.com/jQueryFaviconNotifier/&quot;&gt;Demo on oodavid.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;jQuery Favicon Notifier on GitHub&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/oodavid/jQuery-Favicon-Notifier&quot;&gt;Sources on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lrf6phr1xW1qk6dpq.png&quot; alt=&quot;Conical flash icon with a numerical 4&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;you have 4 new sciences!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Toodles for now!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Chmod issues? A simple fix</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2011/09/09/chmod-issues-a-simple-fix.html"/>
		<updated>2011-09-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2011/09/09/chmod-issues-a-simple-fix</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If (for whatever reason) you mess up the CHMOD permissions for the files and folders, you can run these commands to recursively &amp;quot;reset&amp;quot; all files and folders to their defaults.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;brush: bash;&quot;&gt;find /home/david/Documents/ -type d -print0 | xargs -0 chmod 755
find /home/david/Documents/ -type f -print0 | xargs -0 chmod 644&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BING!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>2011 - my journey so far</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2011/09/09/2011-my-journey-so-far.html"/>
		<updated>2011-09-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2011/09/09/2011-my-journey-so-far</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;2011 has been a bit of an odd one so far; it saw the end of my startup phase and the rebirth of my freelance career. I want to outline the chronology of the year up to now, talk about the future of oodavid and work into a few &amp;quot;freelance lessons&amp;quot; blog posts, so without further ado:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5th January 2011&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following a few face-to-face meetings with the founder of happiest (whom I met at my charity event in 2010) it is explained to me that as 1DayLater is only 2-people it will only go so far, and that I should join his exciting new team as a Director. I wholeheartedly agree!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the next few weeks I wind down my involvement with 1DayLater so that I can get my teeth into writing an API for happiest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;January - June 2011&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fall into a nice routine in the happiest offices; start early, finish late, be punctual, work some weekends - usual startup routine really :-) Over this period I write the API that now powers the happiest platform. Not a lot to say that you can&#39;t imagine; it&#39;s a startup, we do startupish things, technical achievements are made, releases are pushed etc etc etc&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;23rd June 2011&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a short morning meeting, it is decided that I should leave happiest. I give my keys and say adieu. Why am I asked to leave? To this day I&#39;m still unsure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the next few days I mull over the situation and come to some realisations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;I was in a perpetual state of being made a Director - &amp;quot;the lawyers are in next week&amp;quot; etc.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;I was only paid £500 twice - &amp;quot;startup survival invoices&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;I still had 2 unpaid invoices&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Nothing was in writing - every meeting was one-on-one with no witnesses, over the phone, never by email etc.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;All of my code was on their servers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately I deem the first half of 2011 both a success and a failure - SUCCESS! The work I did at happiest was some of the finest of my life - FAILURE! I was duped into giving away my time for essentially free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Last week of June&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I speak to several lawyer associates about my situation and they all have the same thing to say: firstly a sigh of &lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;I&#39;m really sad to hear that&amp;quot;,&lt;/em&gt; followed by &lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;ultimately there&#39;s very little you can do, did you leave a back-door in the system?&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently the legal recourse would be arduous and expensive, but anyhow I am a stickler for the Programmers Code of Ethics; even if there was a back door I wouldn&#39;t use it (there isn&#39;t so don&#39;t try). Petty revenge vs. reputation?! I like my reputation thank you. You live and learn eh?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up I realise that time is of the essence; no point in thinking about happiest now, money is tight at this point and I need to get the word out that I&#39;m back in the game! In 6 hours flat I design and upload a new &lt;a title=&quot;oodavid! what a website you have!&quot; href=&quot;http://oodavid.com/&quot;&gt;oodavid.com&lt;/a&gt;, knock together a quick tumblr blog and start Tweeting and emailing again - it feels amazing :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After this I make a promise to myself - no more startups, time to be the finest freelancer I can be! The last time I was a full-time freelancer was in 2006 and I did very well for myself, but as a 21 year old with no real experience of the world my freelance career was held up by brute force, my technical abilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I make myself another promise - become a master of law and finance as a freelancer, for my health and wealth!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;July&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After putting the word out in June that I&#39;m available for work I am inundated with offers, leads and even requests to join some other startups. I politely decline the startups and get talking to the offers and following the leads. In the between time I research and write up terms and conditions, legal timelines, cashflow logic, monetary projections and the nuances of dealing with bad customers. I must say that they are beautiful; a little symphony of documents that (when used as intended) sing a most calming harmony :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of the month I have signed a 1-week-per-month retainer with one of my old clients - this seriously stabilises my cashflow for the foreseeable future. I start, complete and get paid for 2 small jobs which stabilises my current bank account a little.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;August&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The start of August is primarily concerned with a 3-week job; to create an easily-integrated &amp;quot;Job-Bag-System&amp;quot; for local Ad Agency AdMast. This is a most enjoyable project; essentially a fancy online file manager with multiple file upload, drag and drop functionality, previous versions and the finest feature of all NON-BREAKING-FILE-LINKS. Meaning if you update, rename or move a file, your application will still have access to it via a bridge table. AWESOME.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second half of August is spent in Devon with my gorgeous girlfriend and her family. There is no signal or internet. Life is beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;September&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Returning from Devon I hit the ground running: follow some leads that appeared while I was away, clear the email backlog and almost immediately take the reins for my Dad&#39;s company for the duration of his honeymoon (2 weeks)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly I have my first encounter with late-payments which harks all the way back to June, and that was an invoice with... sure you can guess it... not to worry though, my journey has since showed me something called the Late Payment Legislation, and it&#39;s statutory! Ahhh, the law; you are most excellent :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now and the future&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well here we are: I am 5 days into a very lucrative project which has a great potential for further work; I am working with my Dad and brother again, my finances have been balanced in a manner that will see me out of debt in about 6 months; my legal situation is much better; I have a new flat that has a view of my favourite part of Newcastle; I live 200 metres away from the girl I love. Quite honestly, I&#39;m not sure if I&#39;ve ever been happier - and I&#39;m one of those stupidly optimistic people!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Edit - pretty sure that&#39;s a self-fulfilling feedback loop of optimism and goodness&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blog Posting Uncertainty&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wasn&#39;t entirely sure whether to publish this article but I concluded that if one person can learn from my mistakes I&#39;ll be a better person for it :-)&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>It's time to set my ideas free</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2011/09/08/its-time-to-set-my-ideas-free.html"/>
		<updated>2011-09-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2011/09/08/its-time-to-set-my-ideas-free</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For years I&#39;ve kept &amp;quot;ideas books&amp;quot; as a place to jot down my observations on how to improve things, create new scenarios or even just little thought-puzzles and whatnot. Looking back over them is always quite amusing; some have aged really well and some I&#39;ve seen come to realisation at the hands and minds of others - awesome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lr7138zFwm1qk6dpq.jpg&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;3 of my books&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flicking through the first few pages of the filthy one (2005-2008 I think) I see:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Home energy monitoring kits&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Kinetic mice&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Cashflow projection software&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Super-SImple-Phones&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Stockmarket ideasAn idea for a heist (yes really)&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Audio synthesis interfaces (I have a real big soft-spot for this one)&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Laptop &amp;quot;unfucker&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;A page entitled &amp;quot;when I go to the pub I want to see tea and coffee on draft&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;A game concept called &amp;quot;life&amp;quot; which starts as a sperm-based scrolling shooter / race and evolves with each stage of life&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Artificial Intelligence in Audio Production&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;A logic game called cub3&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Open-Source music (applied to a business model)&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;A time and a place&amp;quot; idea to traverse music throughout time&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Charity concept called &amp;quot;giveback&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Etymological language browser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;and then some&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve come to the conclusion that some of them will likely be unattainable by me and so have decided to find the right company for the idea and will pitching it to them in a short video. I shall immediately write another blog post for the first &amp;quot;pitch&amp;quot;...&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Idea - LloydsTSB Savings Account Wishlist</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2011/09/08/idea-lloydstsb-savings-account-wishlist.html"/>
		<updated>2011-09-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2011/09/08/idea-lloydstsb-savings-account-wishlist</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;An idea to add wishlists to your savings accounts to act as an incentive to save. As you deposit money into the account and pass over monetary thresholds, text messages are sent to you saying something like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;now you have £40 in your account you can afford a new Jumper! Reply BUY to purchase :-)&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://player.vimeo.com/video/28654873?title=0&amp;amp;byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&quot; width=&quot;522&quot; height=&quot;300&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Idea - LloydsTSB Savings Account Wishlist&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>The perks of Working at Home</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2011/08/17/the-perks-of-working-at-home.html"/>
		<updated>2011-08-17T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2011/08/17/the-perks-of-working-at-home</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In my lunch break I get to CHOP-CHOP-KNIFE-FOOD-ATTACK&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lq2u4nbPlT1qk6dpq.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Everything you need for Egg-Fried Rice&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;which turns into some tasty Egg-Fried rice&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lq2u5fY4Gh1qk6dpq.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Egg Fried Rice&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;YOM YOM YOM!!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Desktop error notifications - FOR NERDS</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2011/08/03/desktop-error-notifications-for-nerds.html"/>
		<updated>2011-08-03T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2011/08/03/desktop-error-notifications-for-nerds</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello *nix nerds!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this morning (yes, before breakfast) I awoke the beast of a poota to see a terminal tailing an error log. The tail command with -f flag outputs any changes made to a file, which is well handy to see live errors on your logfiles etc. So if you run something like this in your terminal:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;brush: bash;&quot;&gt;tail -f /var/log/mysql/error.log&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;you would see any mysql errors as they happen, which is pretty cool, but you have to keep a terminal open, switch to it to see the errors etc, which lets be honest is a waste of clicks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back to this morning, I decided that I wanted my errors piped to a notification service and came up with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;brush: bash;&quot;&gt;tail -n0 -f ~/Documents/LOGS/adlink.co.uk.error.log | while read line; do notify-send &quot;adlink.co.uk.error.log&quot; &quot;$line&quot;; done&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;which pushes changes to the notification area, it&#39;s visually lovely:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lpcfvkdGQK1qk6dpq.png&quot; alt=&quot;A &#39;growl-like&#39; notification on the desktop&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;but quickly becomes a pain-in-the-arse for files that are active as each message must wait for the previous to disappear before appearing - resulting in an amazing amount of waiting. So I dug a little deeper and discovered a little program called osd_cat, with which I wrote this command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;brush: bash;&quot;&gt;tail -f ~/Documents/LOGS/adlink.co.uk.error.log | osd_cat --pos bottom --offset 33 --color black --delay 10&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;which as you can see is a bit more nerdy and changes are reflected immediately and layered ontop of everything - perfect!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lpcg0bNlbm1qk6dpq.png&quot; alt=&quot;A textual overlay on the screen - instanty access to error messages&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;so what are you waiting for nerds? GET ON IT&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EDIT - I knocked up a bash script that will tail all the error logs within a directory, so I now run this at startup:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;brush: bash;&quot;&gt;#!/bin/bash

# traverse the directory
for filename in *
do
	# what&#39;s the filename?
	fname=`basename $filename`
	# if it&#39;s an error log
	if [[ $fname == *.error.* ]]
	then
		# tail the file and pipe it to osd_cat
		echo $fname
		tail -f $fname | osd_cat --pos bottom --offset 33 --color black --delay 10 &amp;amp;
	fi
done

exit $?&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extra nerdy++&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>How to test many fonts on your site?</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2011/07/22/how-to-test-many-fonts-on-your-site.html"/>
		<updated>2011-07-22T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2011/07/22/how-to-test-many-fonts-on-your-site</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been pondering today about how the quickest and easiest way to test-drive different fonts, like hundreds of them, on a website... tinkering with the fontsquirrel and google fonts libraries I found myself speccing up a browser plugin / extension based around this piece of code:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;brush: js;&quot;&gt;$(&#39;head&#39;).append(&#39;&amp;lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; href=&quot;http://fonts.googleapis.com/css?family=Lobster+Two&amp;amp;v1&amp;amp;v1&quot; /&amp;gt;&#39;);
$(&#39;body&#39;).css(&#39;font-family&#39;, &quot;&#39;Lobster Two&#39;, arial, serif&quot;);&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...as you can see, if you dumped this into into the console on a site with jQuery it will switch out the font assigned to the body allowing it to cascade down through the DOM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which leaves me with the question; would it be productive to write a chrome extension where you can select any of the freely available hotlinkable fronts and apply it to a website? I think it would! Weekend project here we go :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beer first.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Mike Monteiro says 'F*ck You. Pay Me'</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2011/07/16/mike-monteiro-says-f-ck-you-pay-me.html"/>
		<updated>2011-07-16T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2011/07/16/mike-monteiro-says-f-ck-you-pay-me</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently came across a most excellent video from Mike Monteiro (Web Designer Guru) focussing on the topic of getting paid by clients. It takes a very legal approach (his lawyer is with him onstage) and covers various topics such as kill-fees, your rights as a freelancer, using Intellectual Property as leverage for final payment and introduces several scenarios that are all too familiar with much of the audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://player.vimeo.com/video/22053820?title=0&amp;amp;byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&quot; width=&quot;522&quot; height=&quot;300&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;It&#39;s not as sweary as the title might lead you to think&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk is a contributing factor to my ever growing interest in the legal processes of working freelance or in a small company; My &amp;quot;shitlist&amp;quot; for next week includes creating a legal timeline along with supporting documents, contracts, terms and conditions; I&#39;m even speaking to awesome designer &lt;a title=&#39;Graeme &quot;Grabbins&quot; Metcalfe&#39; href=&quot;http://grabbins.com/&quot;&gt;Graeme &amp;quot;grabbins&amp;quot; Metcalf&lt;/a&gt; about designing a gorgeous one-page infographic that illustrates the process. It&#39;s gonna be gorge.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>The view from my office window</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2011/07/13/the-view-from-my-office-window.html"/>
		<updated>2011-07-13T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2011/07/13/the-view-from-my-office-window</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have always loved Jesmond Dene more than any other part of Newcastle and I&#39;m no so proud to have it as the view from the new home and home-office. I won&#39;t be getting bored of this anytime soon!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lo9ngmthMP1qk6dpq.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Parish Church of St George, Jesmond&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not just on the grounds that it&#39;s a beautiful place, but it&#39;s also my cycling playground where I like to fall off my bike into mud. No really I seem to do that more than anything else there...&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Pure CSS ribbon titles</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2011/07/11/pure-css-ribbon-titles.html"/>
		<updated>2011-07-11T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2011/07/11/pure-css-ribbon-titles</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Being a bit of a non-designer, if I want to add a quick bit of &amp;quot;wheee&amp;quot; to a page I sometimes put my ribbon titles onto my h1, h2, h3 etc tags in order to make them pop a little bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lo6sw97INH1qk6dpq.png&quot; alt=&quot;&#39;Ribbon&#39; Effect using pure CSS&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But until submitting &lt;a title=&quot;Ribbon Titles&quot; href=&quot;http://css1k.com/#ribbon&quot;&gt;my entry onto CSS1K&lt;/a&gt; using such a technique I hadn&#39;t realised that it was considered such a neat trick; I guess you just never know what you&#39;re sitting on!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the trick is wholly inspired by &lt;a title=&quot;Pure CSS Speech Bubbles&quot; href=&quot;http://nicolasgallagher.com/pure-css-speech-bubbles/demo/&quot;&gt;Nicolas Gallagher&#39;s pure css speech bubbles&lt;/a&gt;; however I use 2 pseudo-tags instead of 1. Whether you&#39;ve read and assimilated that link or not, lets code&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;brush: xml;&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;div id=&quot;container&quot;&amp;gt;
	&amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;This is my title&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;style&amp;gt;
	/* Just to align the container */
	#container {width: 400px; margin: 30px auto; text-align: center; padding: 100px 0; background: #EEEEEE;}
	/* The important bit */
	h1 {position: relative; margin: 0 -25px; font-size: 40px; background: #0088AA; color: #FFFFFF; text-shadow: 1px 1px 0px #1A5D6E; box-shadow: 0 0 10px #AAA;}
	h1:after,
	h1:before {content: &quot;&quot;; display: block; position: absolute; bottom: -25px; width: 0; height: 0; border-style: solid; border-color: #1A5D6E transparent;}
	h1:before {border-width: 25px 0 0 25px; left: 0;}
	h1:after  {border-width: 25px 25px 0 0; right: 0;}
&amp;lt;/style&amp;gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And BOOOOOM; ribbons with no extra markup. Awesome. Just tweak the numbers for different sizes, and view the inspiration for the logic and workings (it&#39;s not my place to take credit for that!)&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>I freelance once more!</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2011/06/29/i-freelance-once-more.html"/>
		<updated>2011-06-29T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2011/06/29/i-freelance-once-more</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello world&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a 6 month stint with social startup &lt;a title=&quot;happiest - positively social&quot; href=&quot;http://happie.st/&quot;&gt;happiest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; I find myself re-kindling my freelancing career, before I can begin touting for work I have a rather long list of due-diligence that must be completed, the meat of which comprises of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update &lt;a title=&quot;David King - creative problem solver - web developer and programmer&quot; href=&quot;http://oodavid.com&quot;&gt;oodavid.com&lt;/a&gt; to act as my portfolio&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;something quick and succinct, with testimonials and a call-to-action&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update my legal documents and contracts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&#39;m making some changes on account of recent lessons learned&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Formalise my agile processes for new clients&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;I used to work on an ad-hoc basis which is fine when working with decent clients however the past 3 years of startup culture has brought agile to the table, awesome&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rebuild my network of freelances with whom I can rely on&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I last freelanced over 3 years ago and my little black book does no justice to the excellent freelancers and talents that I&#39;ve encountered in my time away&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve given myself a fortnight to complete these tasks and I&#39;m looking forward to each and every one of them! And with that I must big you adieu, I&#39;m ahead of schedule and am starting to plough through my legal documents. Awesome... &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;All coders have to write that on a new blog, just the way it is :-)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&#39;ll be writing about my work at happiest in another blog post in the future :-)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Designing - Why the 12 column layout is awesome</title>
		<link href="http://oodavid.com/2011/06/29/designing-why-the-12-column-layout-is-awesome.html"/>
		<updated>2011-06-29T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
		<id>http://oodavid.com.com/2011/06/29/designing-why-the-12-column-layout-is-awesome</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When designing interfaces for the web, a lot of people use the &lt;a title=&quot;960 Grid System&quot; href=&quot;http://960.gs&quot;&gt;960 grid system&lt;/a&gt; or something similar as a layout system. Loving numbers as I do, &lt;em&gt;I have π tattooed on my arm after all&lt;/em&gt;, I decided to explore the reasoning and logic behind the much adopted 960 system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 12 column layout that is core to the system is a &lt;a title=&quot;Highly Composite Numbers on Wikipedia&quot; href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Highly_composite_number&quot;&gt;highly composite number&lt;/a&gt; ie. it has a large number of divisors; 1, 2, 3, 4, 6 or 12 even columns to be precise - AWESOME. So this means when you go about designing your layout you have a great deal of flexibility and choice - ♥ MATH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Short and sweet blog today as I am moving into a new apartment! It&#39;s a lovely place on Osborne Road in Jesmond, more on that later :-)&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
</feed>